<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Tagged 'personal-essays', Sightless Scribbles</title>
  <subtitle>A fabulously gay blind author.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/posts/tags/personal-essays/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/" />
  <updated>2024-08-30T00:38:46Z</updated>
  <id>https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Kingett</name>
    <email>kingettr@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Trunk Writing</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6625/" />
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:38:46Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6625/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If the below does not work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting&quot;&gt;go to the books page directly, here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting/embed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pass the Salt</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6522/" />
    <updated>2024-03-24T18:30:29Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6522/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Publisher: &lt;a href=&quot;https://compassiviste.com/initiative/compassiviste-publishing/&quot;&gt;Compassiviste Publishing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online dating is never easy. You’re meeting a complete stranger, and you’re opening yourself up in a way that some of your best friends don’t even get to see. But when Robert Kingett stepped out onto the dating scene, he faced a whole host of additional challenges as a gay man living with blindness, cerebral palsy, and a speech impediment. Pass the Salt details Robert’s time on the dating scene in 2010s Chicago. Get ready to meet the brightest and best from the online dating world, including The Fare Fan, The Smooth Catfish, and the dashing Richard, who’s better company than Robert’s humming fridge. It’s a hilarious and often moving account of his adventures, guaranteed to make you laugh, make you think, and above all, inspire you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-ebook&quot;&gt;Buy the eBook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassiviste.com/product/pass-the-salt/&quot;&gt;Buy from the publisher.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-print-book&quot;&gt;Buy the print book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-audiobook&quot;&gt;Buy the Audiobook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Save the World- The Compassiviste Anthology: Volume One: Visions for Peace</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6517/" />
    <updated>2024-03-11T19:41:02Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6517/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/IMG_2244-scaled-7Ct5npA0gcu3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It has the title &amp;quot;How to Change the World- The Compassiviste Anthology&amp;quot; in white text on a grey background, running vertically down the left-hand side of the cover. Across the top, in black block letters, it reads &amp;quot;Volume One: Visions for Peace.&amp;quot; In the centre of the cover, there is an abstract group of figures holding each other. It&#39;s unclear whether they are male or female, or what race they are. The image is mostly black and white, with an orange streak circling the figures. The Compassiviste logo (an orange C) is in the bottom left-hand corner.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cover description provided by the publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has the title &amp;quot;How to Change the World- The Compassiviste Anthology&amp;quot; in white text on a grey background, running vertically down the left-hand side of the cover. Across the top, in black block letters, it reads &amp;quot;Volume One: Visions for Peace.&amp;quot; In the centre of the cover, there is an abstract group of figures holding each other. It’s unclear whether they are male or female, or what race they are. The image is mostly black and white, with an orange streak circling the figures. The Compassiviste logo (an orange C) is in the bottom left-hand corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher: &lt;a href=&quot;https://compassivistepublishing.com/contact/&quot;&gt;Compassiviste Publishing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-anthology&quot;&gt;About the anthology.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to live in harmony? Is true peace even possible? And how do we continue to live meaningful lives when conflict seems so inescapable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this collection of essays, short stories, book extracts and poetry, authors from around the world reflect on the theme “Visions for Peace” and what it means to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All profits from the sale of How to Change the World: The Compassiviste Anthology go to the Compassiviste Foundation to help build a fairer and more harmonious Planet Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributors include: Carl M.A. Arden, Joe Bisicchia, Bhargavi Chatterjea Bhattacharyya, BA Brittingham, Vanessa Caraveo, Binod Dawadi, Libby Hoffman, Ali Horriyat, Stacey Huish, Barbara Anna Gaiardoni, Nitsan Joy Gordon, Robert Kingett, Rebecca Klassen, Christine Law, Allan Lake, Anna Maria Mickiewicz, Davion Moore, Jon Nakapalau, James B. Nicola, Honey Novick, KV Raghupathi, CLS Sandoval, Ndaba Sibanda, SP Singh, and Lynn White.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-ebook&quot;&gt;Buy the eBook.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/visions-for-peace-compassiviste-authors-collective/1145056316?ean=2940179734314&quot;&gt;Buy on Barns and Noble.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kobo.com/au/en/ebook/visions-for-peace&quot;&gt;Buy on Kobo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Save-World-Compassiviste-Anthology-ebook/dp/B0CW1FVQSC/ref=sr_1_1?dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.3VMDJ3WhIPl1NZ3o0Xmi_Q.2BIpD8QiZcu9ZaZwpUA0CABVH-8T6cX0eEp6ztqboq0&amp;amp;dib_tag=se&amp;amp;qid=1710159938&amp;amp;refinements=p_27%3ACompassiviste+Authors%27+Collective&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;text=Compassiviste+Authors%27+Collective&quot;&gt;Buy on Amazon.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing the BOOK</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6514/" />
    <updated>2024-03-10T00:08:09Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6514/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can’t believe I came up with this in high school! I was digging around old flash drives and found this. Ironically, I think I captured the tech culture that plagues us today. If you show this to a tech bro, I wonder if his eyes will light up like a Christmas tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly don’t know what I was going for back then, but if I were to write this today, I’d make some clearer jabs at tech lovers and tech enthusiasts, but all in all, I think I did well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-book&quot;&gt;The BOOK.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Robert Kingett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a new revolutionary piece of technology out there on the market today that can very much &amp;quot;expand&amp;quot; the lives of others. It is called the Brevity of Optical Knowledge, or it’s more common name, BOOK. The BOOK is very advanced when it comes to information storage. Compacting over 97,000 characters into its memory banks, the BOOK is a very easy to use and affordable piece of equipment packed with tons of features, maps, entertainment articles, and even some games from time to time, and it all fits in the palm of your hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK uses a special black symbol creator to display its information to the naked eye. With striking contrast yet clear precise type, the user will have no issues reading the information that is displayed on the bound viewing pad. Certain models of the Book have enlarged text so those with visual impairments or reading difficulties can easily decipher what’s on the viewing pad. This new character generator will make it easy to navigate the vast array of information stored within the BOOK’s memory. Many users will love the ease of access that the BOOK has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK can also display elaborate graphic designs, charts, and even graphs. It displays these graphical drawings precisely to scale on the view pad, and in some instances, the graphs are even color coded by a special optical generating device that allows the user to automatically receive the transmitted color coordinated information. Some models of the BOOK have tactile representations that pop out of the viewing pad for younger users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK is even portable. With dimensions of 6 x 9 inches for a new softly bound model or 8.5 x 11 for a hardbound model, the BOOK can be taken anywhere, and used anywhere. However, the user must use both hands to initialize the program within. The user must also be near some sort of light source to see the information the BOOK displays on its viewing pad. For those dark environments, the BOOK does offer audio-based versions so users can enjoy the program even without a light source, or when they are busy, or if they have trouble deciphering what’s on the viewing pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each model of the BOOK has a self-contained program that, when activated, will fire the powerful virtual reality neural network in the brain to give users an authentic reenactment experience as users decipher the code on the viewing pad or by listening to the audio model. Not all users of the BOOK will be able to use these virtual reality experiences because they’ve suppressed their imagination. Users with limited imagination will not be able to take full advantage of the virtual reality experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK has the ability to automatically show the viewer a sneak peak at what the particular package contains within. Displaying the information summery in a vertical column running down the left side of the preview screen before the program starts, users can quickly look and see what’s contained in the unit. It will even give the section so that users can quickly navigate to the proper point. This advanced indexing system isn’t available in all versions of the BOOK, but most packages offer this extra feature at no cost to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK even has an extension which will mark your place for you. The extension has munificent elaborate computer-generated designs that are easy to see and distinguish. This extension is commonly referred to as the BOOKMARK. Unlike imagination, the BOOKMARK is an accessory that is sold separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK is very affordable. With its vast array of information and features, most versions of the BOOK are available for a one-time price of &#92;$12.00 at most venders across the United States. Training may be required to use the BOOK, but the department of education has made it a law to allow all people regardless of disability, race, creed, sexual orientation, or religion to receive training for the BOOK. Training usually starts at about six years old, and training may speed or decrease depending on the user’s knowledge of the BOOK’s internal code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK is available in all major carriers across the world. You can even try the BOOK for a minimum of two weeks at certain testing facilities around the world created by adults that believe sharing is caring, which comes dangerously close to socialism, but you must acquire a card to be able to access these testing centers. Not everyone can impersonate a person, so we want to make sure that it is in fact, you, who wishes to test out the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developers of the BOOK put a lot of time and effort into making the proper display, program, and casing. The BOOK is durable but handle the equipment with care. There isn’t a warranty available for the BOOK yet, but there is a money back guarantee option that you automatically get when at certain venders that carry the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK will be available everywhere, and this is a new piece of technology that you don’t want to miss. With clear precise lazar technology, images and texts are displayed on a nice white screen with black shading, an advanced navigation system, and an innovative user interface, the BOOK just may be the highlight of today. The BOOK will be released sometime this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Journalism and essays.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5836/" />
    <updated>2023-02-08T05:10:52Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5836/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before I &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/books/&quot;&gt;became a romance writer,&lt;/a&gt; I was a journalist covering a wide array of beats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That work was very fulfilling. &lt;a href=&quot;https://muckrack.com/weirdwriter&quot;&gt;View my journalism profile&lt;/a&gt; or check out other links below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://muckrack.com/weirdwriter/articles&quot;&gt;View all bylines.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://muckrack.com/weirdwriter/portfolio&quot;&gt;Portfolio and highlights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Forget You&amp;#8217;re Blind.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5677/" />
    <updated>2022-10-10T23:35:52Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5677/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The below comic was a collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ADayintheLifeofaPWD?__cft__%5B0%5D=AZU0QuutWPYhyz1hsynMFHV3ww2lRhdqG7hETPSkaG-xbT1V_bXgHW3MFy7SxziX0-q6CFiWweeyuS0TSi_5j8VPHhq2Li0vv1NDL92FJlH8byE83FdijzxxOlQcWrkmory_g43A9qnE0-A1mPfMlGpELqyFhBPrt9vo22RwOs9H2PDFtVlAAqjb_uIgrrrHslI&amp;amp;__tn__=-UC%2CP-R&quot;&gt;A Day in the Life of a PWD, Person With a Disability.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They created the comic. I just provided the frame ideas and dialog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the comic below or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=479531937552074&amp;amp;set=a.466461358859132&amp;amp;__cft__%5B0%5D=AZX9JIbwRWgOMECQA4dYle54VxtYZWueCX9hiPC6V8p_gVlsr_RVBKVL_DEFNh5QuXvcIte5Q8aBTeMFBig1t3XadJo4IY2v4UAOKRv13CpfdM8Bnet3asj4huZC_SfrATEFu3brBDVhbzRc6QcNRYU6&amp;amp;__tn__=EH-R&quot;&gt;read the comic on Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/blind-man-chips-comic.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/blind-man-chips-comic-62x192-WWF3LA1GRu6U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;COMIC STRIP. Frame 1. A blind man who uses a white cane is sitting in a living room with three friends. MAN: Hey, could someone pass me some chips? Frame 2. FRIEND, Sure, man, here ya go! The friend tosses a bag of chips across the room. It sails past the man&#39;s head. The other two friends look stunned. Frame 3. FRIEND, Aw, man! Sorry. Sometimes I forget you&#39;re blind. Exasperated, the man rolls his eyes, and the other two stare at the friend in awkward silence.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;comic-description&quot;&gt;Comic description.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COMIC STRIP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ADayintheLifeofaPWD?__cft__%5B0%5D=AZU0QuutWPYhyz1hsynMFHV3ww2lRhdqG7hETPSkaG-xbT1V_bXgHW3MFy7SxziX0-q6CFiWweeyuS0TSi_5j8VPHhq2Li0vv1NDL92FJlH8byE83FdijzxxOlQcWrkmory_g43A9qnE0-A1mPfMlGpELqyFhBPrt9vo22RwOs9H2PDFtVlAAqjb_uIgrrrHslI&amp;amp;__tn__=-UC%2CP-R&quot;&gt;A Day in the Life of a PWD, Person With a Disability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blind man who uses a white cane is sitting in a living room with three friends. MAN: Hey, could someone pass me some chips?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRIEND: Sure, man, here ya go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The friend tosses a bag of chips across the room. It sails past the man’s head. The other two friends look stunned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRIEND: Aw, man! Sorry. Sometimes I forget you’re blind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exasperated, the man rolls his eyes, and the other two stare at the friend in awkward silence&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>About me in my own words.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5655/" />
    <updated>2022-06-23T09:42:02Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5655/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This originally appeared in Bold Blind Beauty in June 2020. The website appears to have shut down so I am printing this essay here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;born-a-miracle&quot;&gt;Born A Miracle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been somewhat of a miracle baby, or person, I guess you could say now. I fully embrace it, though, and yes, even the inspirational label that gets placed on me sometimes. I embrace it all because I just simply don’t have time to quibble over a slightly incorrect label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My miracle journey started in 1989 where I was a premature baby. It’s so wild, because my birth certificate says six ounces. I was born in September. I have no idea when I was actually supposed to be born, but I came out defying all odds from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born with Retinopathy of prematurity (ROP), as well as cerebral palsy. I wasn’t supposed to walk. I wasn’t supposed to talk either. My mobility was supposed to be very limited throughout my whole life. And, to a certain extent, that’s true now that I’m older, but back then, I did walk, and I did talk. I overcame so much at such a young age. I still had communication issues though. I stammered badly as a kid and still do. Which, ironically, is why I enjoy and embrace writing so feverishly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-his-terms&quot;&gt;On His Terms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born in New York but grew up in Saint Augustine FL. I attended the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind and that’s how my path to adaptive technology and accessibility consulting came to be, but more on that later. I’m probably one of the very few kids that actively refused mainstream school. I rejected it firmly. I hated the thought of attending a mainstream school. I knew I was getting the adaptive technology and mobility training that would help me later on in life. I didn’t want to waste my time advocating for everything under the sun. I knew that advocacy would come later, certainly, in college, so I wanted my high school to be as painless and as inclusive to my visual impairment as humanly possible and I just didn’t see that in a mainstream school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that society saw me as another worldly being that wasn’t worth nurturing as a disabled person, so I perceived mainstream school to just be an academic hassle. It probably would have done wonders for my social life, but I didn’t care about having an active social life when I was younger. I also didn’t want to be around sighted people unless it was on my own terms because, I believed, that my academics would suffer because I’d be trying to develop social justifications. I thought my energy would be wiped because I’d have to constantly demonstrate to sighted people that I’m worthy of existing and taken seriously. At a blind school, disabilities didn’t factor into my acceptance so I could focus on my education without worrying about social norms or fitting in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason why a big part of that unwillingness to fight for a mainstream education was so strong is because I was getting a very accessible education. I also was just trying to get through the day, and to my eventual long-term goal of becoming influential. Even if it was silent influence, I wanted to actively chip away at the social barriers disabled people face on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-scrapper-to-success&quot;&gt;From Scrapper To Success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My home life wasn’t that great. I was abused, both physically, mentally, emotionally, and otherwise. My mother, who was a single parent, didn’t know how to deal with her own daemons so she took them out on me. She was a heavy drinker and, yes, there would be beatings. I often went hungry, so I absolutely empathize with someone when they tell people they don’t know what real hunger feels like. People will never fully grasp it, I realized, so I just had to survive. Get out. Become as successful as I could possibly be and hope I make a small difference in the world, even if it’s educating someone about blindness or starts a chain reaction that makes things more accessible for many in my generation and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I developed a strong sense of advocacy in my teen years. I’ve never been good at giving a punchy media bite that goes viral or gets people talking. I knew I’d never be in the spotlight however, I knew my strength was in planning and strategic implementations. Oh, and trickle-down advocacy—chain reaction advocacy, as I call it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m very career-driven, and very focused, which is probably why I’m still single. I’m very proudly gay and or queer. I use those words interchangeably to describe my sexuality. I’m definitely not bisexual though, I’m very much gay. But, often, the men I’m attracted to are sighted and have no idea how to keep up with my career drive. That’s something that will, eventually, slow down I’m sure as I get even older, but for now, I’m very focused. I find the idea of romance and love is just something that I will find when it finds me, and grabs hold of me. That’s ironic because I’m an extremely romantic person. I’m very empathetic but extremely strong, personality-wise. I guess you could say I’m a mashup of imperfections that changes people’s lives in small ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path-to-journalism&quot;&gt;The Path To Journalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advocacy started when I created the first-ever newspaper for the blind at FSDB. That proved to me that I could give people chances and opportunities if I just kept being persistent. As a result, well, I’m Very forward-thinking and I’m a proud feminist and trans ally. I knew I had the power to change lives through journalism and fiction, so I began writing. Fiction, advocacy journeys, telling people’s stories. I find that very few people have media literacy skills. I read, constantly. I even read mainstream news everybody likes to rag on so much, but again, very few people just simply don’t know how the media works in general, which is why I don’t get into small fights online about mainstream media and agendas and biases and otherwise. It’s all trite ignorance and a complete waste of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My writing eventually created the Accessible Netflix Project, which actually got Netflix to provide audio description platform-wide wherever possible. This was a huge accomplishment, but my work isn’t over with. My real love is books. Especially diverse books, and audiobooks, and the publishing industry. I’m working to eventually make it so that seeing blindness in fiction is common while continuing to be a very strong ally to my fellow minorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;unicorns-cookies-and-education&quot;&gt;Unicorns, Cookies &amp;amp; Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always find it really weird when someone asks me what my hobbies are. My hobbies are extremely plain and ordinary. Like, who doesn’t like listening to music and watching TV shows with audio description? I know a few people who don’t like reading, but I just imagine them as very confused unicorns and continue loving books and literature. I read, certainly. I watch very dark comedy. I listen to boy bands. I steal rainbow tinged cookies from unsuspecting glittering cats in my spare time. I’m so done with being normal. It’s overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically speaking, my career path has never been regular, either. I dropped out of college, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/books/&quot;&gt;published several books,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/shorts/&quot;&gt;wrote short stories,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/writings/&quot;&gt;wrote nonfiction&lt;/a&gt; that makes people laugh, did accessibility consulting, and, finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/resume/&quot;&gt;wear a lot of other hats as well.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take this opportunity to tell all the readers to stay in school. Seriously. I think education is the most important facet in someone’s life. Encourage reading. Encourage creativity, because that’s what truly makes the world go round.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
