<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Tagged 'Mailing list', Sightless Scribbles</title>
  <subtitle>A fabulously gay blind author.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/posts/tags/mailing-list/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/" />
  <updated>2024-03-25T20:44:36Z</updated>
  <id>https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Kingett</name>
    <email>kingettr@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Two new books to buy from me.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6525/" />
    <updated>2024-03-25T20:44:36Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6525/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Surprise! I have news! I’m publishing something new!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it’s two things. One is a contribution to the anthology &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/6517/&quot;&gt;How to Save the World.&lt;/a&gt; I published a personal essay about my experiences becoming a penpal for prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is a book I’m super excited to share! &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/6522/&quot;&gt;Pass the Salt&lt;/a&gt; is a nonfiction collection of personal essays about the dating experience in Chicago in the 2010s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pass the Salt is funny, heartwarming, touching, and it’s just a snapshot of goodness. I hope you all really enjoy the book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best page to keep up with book formats and where to get it is on &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/6522/&quot;&gt;this book landing page.&lt;/a&gt; As formats become available, I’ll put them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned because lots of interviews are coming about the book and my overall experiences. I’m so happy to finally release this out into the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Library spotlight: Queer Liberation Library.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6358/" />
    <updated>2023-12-20T16:28:41Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6358/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book censorship is very, very, important to me, so when I see libraries that directly challenge book censorship, well, I love them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/myblog/posts/tags/blog-and-journal&quot;&gt;written many times in my blog about why I love libraries&lt;/a&gt; and detest book censorship. I’m here to promote a free nationwide library for the USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.queerliberationlibrary.org/&quot;&gt;Queer Liberation Library&lt;/a&gt; is a digital library that uses the Libby app as their library platform. It’s free for anyone in the US to sign up, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://givebutter.com/DLwIaj&quot;&gt;donate your money to Queer Liberation Library&lt;/a&gt; or send someone the registration link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.queerliberationlibrary.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.queerliberationlibrary.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
