<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Tagged 'writings', Sightless Scribbles</title>
  <subtitle>A fabulously gay blind author.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/posts/tags/writings/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/" />
  <updated>2024-10-13T09:52:58Z</updated>
  <id>https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Kingett</name>
    <email>kingettr@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Thomas Was Alone PS3 review.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6642/" />
    <updated>2024-10-13T09:52:58Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6642/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the website that hosted this review is no longer online, so I am posting it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was also back when I had some vision. I am fully blind now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-details&quot;&gt;Game Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version tested: PS3Also available on: PC, PS Vita&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer: Mike Bithell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher: Mike Bithell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genre: Puzzle Platformer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-review&quot;&gt;The Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;   April 4th 2014 Robert Kingett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a definition to many different words tucked away in a video game dictionary somewhere. The definition is overlooked because it’s an indie title developed by one man with a mission to bring so many workable elements into a puzzle platformer that it makes some blockbuster titles begging for the same gripping emersion. The definition lies beneath the words, &amp;quot;accessible, rich, engaging, unforgettable, and even ambitious.&amp;quot; Thomas Was Alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Was Alone&lt;/em&gt; is a beautifully designed game because everything about the game is really playable to disabled gamers and non-disabled gamers alike, even one-handed gamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many different types of gamers will instantly enjoy the characters that are different quadrilaterals on a quest for greatness as well as discovery as they jump with whimsical observations, empowering heroic thoughts, amiable love, and a chic sense of pride with a wild mesh of beliefs, emotions, and characters narrated splendidly by Danny Wallace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game mechanic is very simple. The gameplay premise could hardly be simpler: each level tasks you with getting one or more colored quadrilaterals to the portal (a basic white outline) which matches its shape.) This is achieved by navigating a surplus array of mind warping puzzles, jumping from platform to platform as well as switching characters in order to get them where they should be. By jumping with the jump button, in this case, X, and switching characters with the shoulder buttons, the puzzles will soon be just as memorable as the story, even to disabled gamers because emphasis is placed on brain function rather than limb function. This makes the game far more accessible to the physically disabled than most blockbuster titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visuals are easy for the visually impaired to see, with all surfaces being a black outline and the character’s stark colors and shapes, making them very distinguishable visually alongside from their personalities.&#92;&lt;br&gt;
The game is subtitled, though deaf gamers may get annoyed because the subtitles are not static. They move with the character being controlled, and this could make it hard to read the subtitles. The text, however, can be placed onto any environmental background and that will help work around that factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is memorable because Danny Wallace injects the player with many different emotions, narrative fervor, and character depth into syllables and sentences crafted with obviously careful word choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players will meet Thomas, an average block that can do everything averagely with the added bonus of hilarious observation, and uncanny wisdom that sometimes annoys the rest of his friends. Chris, the block who struggles with identity and purpose more so than any other character because his weight inhibits his jumping, and who needs an endless supply of hugs to boost his tormented dormant spirit. Laura, a thin pink flat block that can bounce the other’s to new heights while dealing with the love in her heart for Chris. Claire, a blue superhero with the misleading power to float on water and have an extreme sense of resolution to aid. James, a green block that navigates the puzzles in a unique way where he sticks to the roof rather than the ground, wondering why differences are so differently viewed among the world with musings of hope and acceptance. Jon, a thin yellow stick that soars as high as his boisterous ego, and finally, Sarah, the double jumping mystical vat of weird declarations of intensions laced with power behind each thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each character has their own purpose and will need to be utilized, sometimes all at once in a puzzle that utilizes all of their abilities, sometimes with only one of the many wonderful personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disabled gamers won’t have a problem with the game at all because everything is very streamlined and plain, making for vast customization types, such as using the analog stick instead of the D pad to move characters. Even people who use one-handed controllers could play this game without assistance because the challenge lies within tacking new challenges onto the brain and not the limbs with a variety of jumping puzzles. The most complicated aspect of the game is making staircases with the characters in order to progress certain characters, but those scenarios happen sporadically and don’t hinder gameplay for very long. The more it’s required the more comfortable and natural it is to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Was Alone&lt;/em&gt; gives an all-encompassing experience that’s nestled inside a marvelously crafted world of stories, friends, and jumping. Disabled and non-disabled alike will easily remember the dashing characters and elegant level designs nestled inside of a very solid framework that stands tall and strong amongst bigger titles. The numerous memorabilia sprinkled throughout this game definitely show how even the simplest of implementations can be crafted with vivid vision into something that’s both mind blowing, and inclusive for the disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Trunk Writing</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6625/" />
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:38:46Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6625/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If the below does not work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting&quot;&gt;go to the books page directly, here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting/embed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pass the Salt</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6522/" />
    <updated>2024-03-24T18:30:29Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6522/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Publisher: &lt;a href=&quot;https://compassiviste.com/initiative/compassiviste-publishing/&quot;&gt;Compassiviste Publishing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online dating is never easy. You’re meeting a complete stranger, and you’re opening yourself up in a way that some of your best friends don’t even get to see. But when Robert Kingett stepped out onto the dating scene, he faced a whole host of additional challenges as a gay man living with blindness, cerebral palsy, and a speech impediment. Pass the Salt details Robert’s time on the dating scene in 2010s Chicago. Get ready to meet the brightest and best from the online dating world, including The Fare Fan, The Smooth Catfish, and the dashing Richard, who’s better company than Robert’s humming fridge. It’s a hilarious and often moving account of his adventures, guaranteed to make you laugh, make you think, and above all, inspire you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-ebook&quot;&gt;Buy the eBook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassiviste.com/product/pass-the-salt/&quot;&gt;Buy from the publisher.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-print-book&quot;&gt;Buy the print book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-the-audiobook&quot;&gt;Buy the Audiobook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing the BOOK</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6514/" />
    <updated>2024-03-10T00:08:09Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6514/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can’t believe I came up with this in high school! I was digging around old flash drives and found this. Ironically, I think I captured the tech culture that plagues us today. If you show this to a tech bro, I wonder if his eyes will light up like a Christmas tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly don’t know what I was going for back then, but if I were to write this today, I’d make some clearer jabs at tech lovers and tech enthusiasts, but all in all, I think I did well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-book&quot;&gt;The BOOK.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Robert Kingett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a new revolutionary piece of technology out there on the market today that can very much &amp;quot;expand&amp;quot; the lives of others. It is called the Brevity of Optical Knowledge, or it’s more common name, BOOK. The BOOK is very advanced when it comes to information storage. Compacting over 97,000 characters into its memory banks, the BOOK is a very easy to use and affordable piece of equipment packed with tons of features, maps, entertainment articles, and even some games from time to time, and it all fits in the palm of your hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK uses a special black symbol creator to display its information to the naked eye. With striking contrast yet clear precise type, the user will have no issues reading the information that is displayed on the bound viewing pad. Certain models of the Book have enlarged text so those with visual impairments or reading difficulties can easily decipher what’s on the viewing pad. This new character generator will make it easy to navigate the vast array of information stored within the BOOK’s memory. Many users will love the ease of access that the BOOK has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK can also display elaborate graphic designs, charts, and even graphs. It displays these graphical drawings precisely to scale on the view pad, and in some instances, the graphs are even color coded by a special optical generating device that allows the user to automatically receive the transmitted color coordinated information. Some models of the BOOK have tactile representations that pop out of the viewing pad for younger users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK is even portable. With dimensions of 6 x 9 inches for a new softly bound model or 8.5 x 11 for a hardbound model, the BOOK can be taken anywhere, and used anywhere. However, the user must use both hands to initialize the program within. The user must also be near some sort of light source to see the information the BOOK displays on its viewing pad. For those dark environments, the BOOK does offer audio-based versions so users can enjoy the program even without a light source, or when they are busy, or if they have trouble deciphering what’s on the viewing pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each model of the BOOK has a self-contained program that, when activated, will fire the powerful virtual reality neural network in the brain to give users an authentic reenactment experience as users decipher the code on the viewing pad or by listening to the audio model. Not all users of the BOOK will be able to use these virtual reality experiences because they’ve suppressed their imagination. Users with limited imagination will not be able to take full advantage of the virtual reality experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK has the ability to automatically show the viewer a sneak peak at what the particular package contains within. Displaying the information summery in a vertical column running down the left side of the preview screen before the program starts, users can quickly look and see what’s contained in the unit. It will even give the section so that users can quickly navigate to the proper point. This advanced indexing system isn’t available in all versions of the BOOK, but most packages offer this extra feature at no cost to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK even has an extension which will mark your place for you. The extension has munificent elaborate computer-generated designs that are easy to see and distinguish. This extension is commonly referred to as the BOOKMARK. Unlike imagination, the BOOKMARK is an accessory that is sold separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK is very affordable. With its vast array of information and features, most versions of the BOOK are available for a one-time price of &#92;$12.00 at most venders across the United States. Training may be required to use the BOOK, but the department of education has made it a law to allow all people regardless of disability, race, creed, sexual orientation, or religion to receive training for the BOOK. Training usually starts at about six years old, and training may speed or decrease depending on the user’s knowledge of the BOOK’s internal code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK is available in all major carriers across the world. You can even try the BOOK for a minimum of two weeks at certain testing facilities around the world created by adults that believe sharing is caring, which comes dangerously close to socialism, but you must acquire a card to be able to access these testing centers. Not everyone can impersonate a person, so we want to make sure that it is in fact, you, who wishes to test out the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developers of the BOOK put a lot of time and effort into making the proper display, program, and casing. The BOOK is durable but handle the equipment with care. There isn’t a warranty available for the BOOK yet, but there is a money back guarantee option that you automatically get when at certain venders that carry the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BOOK will be available everywhere, and this is a new piece of technology that you don’t want to miss. With clear precise lazar technology, images and texts are displayed on a nice white screen with black shading, an advanced navigation system, and an innovative user interface, the BOOK just may be the highlight of today. The BOOK will be released sometime this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Deserving Conference</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6380/" />
    <updated>2023-12-24T03:58:15Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6380/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A text version and audio version is below. &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting&quot;&gt;Buy DRM free A Deserving Conference here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story features on-page psychological abuse. Take care of yourself before reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-podcast-audio-version&quot;&gt;Initial Podcast/audio version.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final podcast from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brickmoonentertainment.com/2018/11/07/commentsection/&quot;&gt;the anthology IT CAME FROM THE COMMENT SECTION!&lt;/a&gt; couldn’t be more appropriate or seasonal.  Typically our writer’s run dark –  maybe that’s just the nature of creating compelling stories.  But every now and then we get a story that’s full of empathy and compassion – a story such as this one from Robert Kingett.  Please enjoy this personal and heartfelt tale that celebrates selflessness and humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://content.blubrry.com/bmf_podcast/Deserving_Conference_A-Brick_Moon_Fiction.mp3&quot;&gt;Download the MP3.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Came-Comment-Section-Lauren-Forry-ebook/dp/B07K7S3KXD/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1541612044&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=it+came+from+the+comment+section&amp;amp;dpID=51lnbRUMnZL&amp;amp;preST=_SY445_QL70_&amp;amp;dpSrc=srch&quot;&gt;Buy the print anthology on Amazon.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;updated-print-version&quot;&gt;Updated print version.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting&quot;&gt;Download the updated story here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pointy Chances</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6331/" />
    <updated>2023-12-19T05:53:37Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6331/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The below story first appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://atthisarts.com/product/community-of-magic-pens/&quot;&gt;the Community of Magic Pens anthology&lt;/a&gt; but &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/trunkwriting&quot;&gt;find the updated version in this bundle.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Forget You&amp;#8217;re Blind.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5677/" />
    <updated>2022-10-10T23:35:52Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5677/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The below comic was a collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ADayintheLifeofaPWD?__cft__%5B0%5D=AZU0QuutWPYhyz1hsynMFHV3ww2lRhdqG7hETPSkaG-xbT1V_bXgHW3MFy7SxziX0-q6CFiWweeyuS0TSi_5j8VPHhq2Li0vv1NDL92FJlH8byE83FdijzxxOlQcWrkmory_g43A9qnE0-A1mPfMlGpELqyFhBPrt9vo22RwOs9H2PDFtVlAAqjb_uIgrrrHslI&amp;amp;__tn__=-UC%2CP-R&quot;&gt;A Day in the Life of a PWD, Person With a Disability.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They created the comic. I just provided the frame ideas and dialog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the comic below or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=479531937552074&amp;amp;set=a.466461358859132&amp;amp;__cft__%5B0%5D=AZX9JIbwRWgOMECQA4dYle54VxtYZWueCX9hiPC6V8p_gVlsr_RVBKVL_DEFNh5QuXvcIte5Q8aBTeMFBig1t3XadJo4IY2v4UAOKRv13CpfdM8Bnet3asj4huZC_SfrATEFu3brBDVhbzRc6QcNRYU6&amp;amp;__tn__=EH-R&quot;&gt;read the comic on Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/blind-man-chips-comic.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/blind-man-chips-comic-62x192-WWF3LA1GRu6U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;COMIC STRIP. Frame 1. A blind man who uses a white cane is sitting in a living room with three friends. MAN: Hey, could someone pass me some chips? Frame 2. FRIEND, Sure, man, here ya go! The friend tosses a bag of chips across the room. It sails past the man&#39;s head. The other two friends look stunned. Frame 3. FRIEND, Aw, man! Sorry. Sometimes I forget you&#39;re blind. Exasperated, the man rolls his eyes, and the other two stare at the friend in awkward silence.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;comic-description&quot;&gt;Comic description.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COMIC STRIP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ADayintheLifeofaPWD?__cft__%5B0%5D=AZU0QuutWPYhyz1hsynMFHV3ww2lRhdqG7hETPSkaG-xbT1V_bXgHW3MFy7SxziX0-q6CFiWweeyuS0TSi_5j8VPHhq2Li0vv1NDL92FJlH8byE83FdijzxxOlQcWrkmory_g43A9qnE0-A1mPfMlGpELqyFhBPrt9vo22RwOs9H2PDFtVlAAqjb_uIgrrrHslI&amp;amp;__tn__=-UC%2CP-R&quot;&gt;A Day in the Life of a PWD, Person With a Disability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blind man who uses a white cane is sitting in a living room with three friends. MAN: Hey, could someone pass me some chips?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRIEND: Sure, man, here ya go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The friend tosses a bag of chips across the room. It sails past the man’s head. The other two friends look stunned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRIEND: Aw, man! Sorry. Sometimes I forget you’re blind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exasperated, the man rolls his eyes, and the other two stare at the friend in awkward silence&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
