<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Tagged 'roundups', Sightless Scribbles</title>
  <subtitle>A fabulously gay blind author.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/posts/tags/roundups/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/" />
  <updated>2024-04-21T21:50:58Z</updated>
  <id>https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Kingett</name>
    <email>kingettr@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Royalty statement 2023</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6540/" />
    <updated>2024-04-21T21:50:58Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6540/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’d like to show you how much I made for 2023 on my published books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, not so well, but you can read the table below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good thing I have &lt;a href=&quot;/myblog/books&quot;&gt;other books&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/writings/&quot;&gt;other writings&lt;/a&gt; out now, but still, sales matter. Money matters when making art of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really is that simple. If you want artists to keep making art, give them money and buy their work. I wish I had enough money to do more writing, but I simply don’t. I have to focus on living and paying bills and eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-breakdown&quot;&gt;The breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below breaks down &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/4305/&quot;&gt;Artificial Divide&lt;/a&gt; sales by outlet and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to give a hearty shoutout to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nevillepark.ca/&quot;&gt;Neville Park&lt;/a&gt; that assisted me with cleaning up the original PDF. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/4305/&quot;&gt;Artificial Divide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous year balance,-2.025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Divide,15.131,,,,,,,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TOTAL,13.106&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table that was here looked strange, visually speaking, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Artificial-Divide-Earnings-breakdown.html&quot;&gt;read the table here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Artificial Divide Buzz</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6481/" />
    <updated>2024-02-05T17:48:39Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6481/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The below is a short roundup of media/buzz about &lt;a href=&quot;/myblog/posts/4305&quot;&gt;the Artificial Divide anthology.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-works-wonders&quot;&gt;Writing Works Wonders.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://writingworkswonders.com/2021/09/19/ep-28-writing-works-wonders/&quot;&gt;This podcast with Blind writers&lt;/a&gt; has me talking about the anthology and some overall writing and rejection tips. There isn’t a transcript with the episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;down-to-the-struts-podcast&quot;&gt;Down to the Struts podcast.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qudsiya is joined by Robert Kingett, a totally blind, gay, author, essayist and freelance journalist. Qudsiya and Robert discuss Robert’s journey to becoming a writer, the creation of his anthology, Artificial Divide, and why the publishing industry should advance works of fiction created by disabled authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.downtothestruts.com/episodes/season-4-episode-5-robert-kingett&quot;&gt;Episode webpage containing transcript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;vocal-eye-almost-live&quot;&gt;Vocal Eye Almost Live.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VocalEye Almost Live host Amy Amantea is joined by special guests Robert Kingett, Lawrence Gunther, Niki White, and Tessa Soderberg.&lt;br&gt;
Artificial Divide is a new anthology of short fiction by Blind and partially-Blind authors showing readers how they thrive, hurt, get revenge, outsmart bullies, or go on epic adventures. Artificial Divide is an own-voices story collection that captures the many layers of Blindness and, for once, puts blind protagonists in the driver’s seat, letting them take the lead in guiding us on new adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xwAlbc7t4Xc&quot;&gt;Watch VocalEye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-the-cosm-podcast-s1-ep6-the-artificial-divide-with-robert-kingett-and-randy-lacey&quot;&gt;In the ’Cosm Podcast S1, Ep6: The Artificial Divide with Robert Kingett and Randy Lacey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 1 ends with a bang editors Robert Kingett and Randy Lacey speak to me about their upcoming anthology, Artifical Divide. This collection of fiction stories is written by authors who are Blind, visually impaired, or who have low vision.&lt;br&gt;
Transcript and audio podcast links at caitgordon.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://caitgordon.com/2021/05/06/in-the-cosm-podcast-s1-ep6-the-artificial-divide-between-the-blind-and-the-sighted-with-robert-kingett-and-randy-lacey/&quot;&gt;Read the episode transcript&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6a8pg1uPgmo&quot;&gt;Watch The Artificial Divide with Robert Kingett and Randy Lacey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
