<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Tagged 'Throwbacks', Sightless Scribbles</title>
  <subtitle>A fabulously gay blind author.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/posts/tags/throwbacks/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/" />
  <updated>2024-10-14T00:13:45Z</updated>
  <id>https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Kingett</name>
    <email>kingettr@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Hexodius [Xbox 360 Review]</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6646/" />
    <updated>2024-10-14T00:13:45Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6646/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The website that hosted this review is no longer online so I would like to keep it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The below review was written when I was sighted. I am fully blind now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note, nearly 15 years later, this game seems like some serious fun now! I’d gladly go back and time and tell my younger year old self, hey, trust me, when AAA games get flooded with AI junk in the future, a game like this will be very welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-details&quot;&gt;Game details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version tested: Xbox 360&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also available on: PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer: Brain Slap Studio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher: Namco Bandai Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genre: Arena Shooter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-review&quot;&gt;The Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes taking a trip back in time to the days of leaderboards, powerups, and an incentive to show off as you wield weapons is the breath of fresh air that the game industry needs among all the moral dilemmas, side quests, sharing buttons, and effects that cause studios to go completely bankrupt. Even though these old style games were simple in design, they had to be designed with an equal amount of care as today’s blockbuster titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple is all well and good but it’s when the simple aspects of creation feel as if they were designed just to have a finished product flaws start popping up faster than benign tumors. Namco Bandai Games must have had a unique new year’s resolution this year when they designed &lt;em&gt;Hexodius&lt;/em&gt; because the game plays like a half assembled arcade game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its blend of twin-stick shooting, exploration, and customization, &lt;em&gt;Hexodius&lt;/em&gt; invites players to explore the vast complex, equip their drone with powerful items and upgrades, and ultimately escape the clutches of the deadly enemy droids in a blaze of laser fire but the invitation is more tantalizing then the actual party inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This arena style shooter tries hard to be the next &lt;em&gt;Geometry Wars&lt;/em&gt; remake and begs the game for the foundation and salvation, but just fails on many levels. &lt;em&gt;Hexodius&lt;/em&gt; misses almost everything it was going for. There’s a campaign nestled in here somewhere with a story to match, somewhere. I wasn’t able to learn what the story was because, I’m guessing, the story was told via the scrolling text that popped up between the stages but due to the size of the text I might as well have been reading a cuisine menu in Klingon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The campaign opens up to a large hex-grid map — the first of six such worlds in the game that soon look so familiar the level design team could have used them in court to claim copyright infringement on each other. Despite the twiddled down content of the gameplay that will soon have you feeling as if your brain is melting out of your ear, this is a very accessible game to the physically disabled and the colorblind. The left analog stick is used to move and the right is used to shoot. The game is not accessible to anyone with a substantial visual impairment however. It was extremely hard for me to tell the difference between myself and the enemies that came rushing at me from every which direction, showing my cackling friends just how outmatched I was even on the simplest difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few minutes of fun here but the game places a huge emphasis on some things and leaves the rest of the design to wilt like dead flowers. The ship upgrading is expansive, but the level designs could make their own cases for plagiarism, and, coupled with very little enemy verity, it ultimately leaves the wonderment why so much emphasis is placed into the epic customization system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hexodius&lt;/em&gt; is an invite back to the olden days where leaderboards dominated lunch table conversations, but that’s all it is — an invite that makes your tolerance drop quicker than IQ points after watching daytime TV. Despite its ease of playability for the physically disabled, there isn’t even enough verity and content to warrant &lt;em&gt;Hexodius&lt;/em&gt; to be a game — especially for the price it touts on Xbox Live. Gamers with significant visual impairments will have new reasons to question their eyesight, and the true nostalgia hungry fans will be vastly disappointed at the lack of content compared to other games such as &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Geometry Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nihilumbra Review (PC)</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6644/" />
    <updated>2024-10-13T10:09:09Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6644/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the review hosting this isn’t online anymore so I decided to publish it here, on my own website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was back when I had vision. I’m fully blind now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-details&quot;&gt;Game details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version tested: PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also available on: iOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer: BeautiFun Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher: BeautiFun Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genre: Puzzle platformer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-review&quot;&gt;The review.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’d wake up from a terrible nightmare ranging from Stephen King to Donatello from the Ninja Turtles yodeling in my shower, two questions would spring to my mind before I get my wits back. The questions would be &amp;quot;who am I&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;what the heck am I doing here?&amp;quot; as I’d lay back recovering from the shock I would begin to think that the concept of an unknown being would make an epic video game. It seemed as though no one was listening because games with shaky camera angles dominated franchises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my shock though, a developer has tapped into my frontal cortex and developed a game that takes familiar titles and bounces off of their foundation to make a succulent new puzzle platformer that many will underestimate because explosions don’t riddle the screen like excessive confetti. This fresh fun title is Nihilumbra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon playing Nihilumbra one factor will become very apparent quicker than a woman’s last stages of pregnancy. The team at BeautiFun Games has played a few video games in their lifetime and they love the video game world. Evidence is splattered all throughout this graphical holiness because all the aspects that make video games tedious as tax returns are not in Nihilumbra. There are no scavenger hunts repeatedly going back and forth mind-numbingly talking to NPCs. There aren’t any extremely difficult quick time events and there isn’t an online lobby filled with people that the dictionary could use as definitions under &amp;quot;ill-advised&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to judge the game based off of screenshots and video previews because it’s a different kind of game that sucks the player into the void of excitement. Unlike other games taking on the role of interactive movies, you are a being in this world called Born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Born, I was created by a mystical dark entity called the void that was chasing me, bent on capturing me and killing me as I raced through the environments. I, also known as Born, somehow escaped the clutches of the void and now I was to embark on a quest to learn who I was, why was I created, and what my destiny held in store for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the game a voice that could rival any commercial voiceover relayed hints about whom I was and other things about my being and soul as well as provided hints on puzzles. It was an interesting concept that soon had me playing just to learn every facet of my being and purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is an unexpected psychological mind warp that will immediately snatch up attention and hog it, teasing with intriguing misnomers that will soon give way to desires to learn what truth is and what sort of lies hide in this brain bath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling through the five puzzle inducing levels was the icing on top of the very gripping story. As I traversed through icy mountains, forests, caves, deserts, and a city, I was met with a barrage of challenges that would make an IQ test weep. Using the keyboard and mouse I was to paint my way through this side-scroller using colors to interact with my environment and enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each stage introduces a new color, and they are all imbued with specific properties. For example, painting blue on a surface makes it slippery. The slick ground is perfect for making running jumps go further. Once you have gained access to a color, it remains available to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity is encouraged since there were more ways than one to take down enemies using my environment or get through puzzles to find out the Bain of my existence. The will and determination to learn so many unknown aspects about my past, present, and future stretched my creativity to new heights. This game doesn’t have any mind-blowing special effects to gawk at so the desire to play will be solely through the story — a feat that is rare in today’s gaming warehouse. The added Void mode will test creativity even further with no story voiceover, new puzzles, and tougher familiar puzzles daring for a stimulating mental challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The controls are simple and this allowed me to play with minimal problems. I did die an awful lot due to the precision. For disabled gamers the boss sections, where The Void is in hot pursuit and the objective is to escape, as the Void swallows up the left side of the screen, will be the toughest parts. Along with the need for speed disabled gamers will have to quickly paint and quickly switch to needed colors to manipulate objects and this isn’t easy since the game doesn’t pause when you’re switching colors. With my cerebral palsy, I had to modify steam in order to finish the game. To overcome my particular accessibility challenges I used a USB Xbox controller to make painting a bit easier so I didn’t have to rely on friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game does not have a colorblind mode so colorblind gamers will not be able to play the game independently. Even though colors can be chosen on a fixed selection by clicking on a tree branch that’s always at the top right of the screen it will be hard to memorize the colors and see where they have painted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accessibility solution I had to implement made it all that much more rewarding when I finished the game and had my mind blown so vehemently I immediately wanted to play the game again just to try and boost my creativity power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a story that will leave thought waves pulsating to the tune of the excellent writing, intriguing gameplay that breaches boundaries of immersion, and with a Wii U version coming soon that will be much more accessible for those with physical disabilities because the controller will replace a mouse, Nihilumbra is a demonstration of how video games that immerse the player in telling stories, gameplay that challenges the forefront of perception, and having puzzles that will be remembrances at lunch can never be beaten by mainstream titles — no matter how unique the fire particles get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thomas Was Alone PS3 review.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6642/" />
    <updated>2024-10-13T09:52:58Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6642/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the website that hosted this review is no longer online, so I am posting it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was also back when I had some vision. I am fully blind now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-details&quot;&gt;Game Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version tested: PS3Also available on: PC, PS Vita&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer: Mike Bithell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher: Mike Bithell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genre: Puzzle Platformer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-review&quot;&gt;The Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;   April 4th 2014 Robert Kingett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a definition to many different words tucked away in a video game dictionary somewhere. The definition is overlooked because it’s an indie title developed by one man with a mission to bring so many workable elements into a puzzle platformer that it makes some blockbuster titles begging for the same gripping emersion. The definition lies beneath the words, &amp;quot;accessible, rich, engaging, unforgettable, and even ambitious.&amp;quot; Thomas Was Alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Was Alone&lt;/em&gt; is a beautifully designed game because everything about the game is really playable to disabled gamers and non-disabled gamers alike, even one-handed gamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many different types of gamers will instantly enjoy the characters that are different quadrilaterals on a quest for greatness as well as discovery as they jump with whimsical observations, empowering heroic thoughts, amiable love, and a chic sense of pride with a wild mesh of beliefs, emotions, and characters narrated splendidly by Danny Wallace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game mechanic is very simple. The gameplay premise could hardly be simpler: each level tasks you with getting one or more colored quadrilaterals to the portal (a basic white outline) which matches its shape.) This is achieved by navigating a surplus array of mind warping puzzles, jumping from platform to platform as well as switching characters in order to get them where they should be. By jumping with the jump button, in this case, X, and switching characters with the shoulder buttons, the puzzles will soon be just as memorable as the story, even to disabled gamers because emphasis is placed on brain function rather than limb function. This makes the game far more accessible to the physically disabled than most blockbuster titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visuals are easy for the visually impaired to see, with all surfaces being a black outline and the character’s stark colors and shapes, making them very distinguishable visually alongside from their personalities.&#92;&lt;br&gt;
The game is subtitled, though deaf gamers may get annoyed because the subtitles are not static. They move with the character being controlled, and this could make it hard to read the subtitles. The text, however, can be placed onto any environmental background and that will help work around that factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is memorable because Danny Wallace injects the player with many different emotions, narrative fervor, and character depth into syllables and sentences crafted with obviously careful word choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players will meet Thomas, an average block that can do everything averagely with the added bonus of hilarious observation, and uncanny wisdom that sometimes annoys the rest of his friends. Chris, the block who struggles with identity and purpose more so than any other character because his weight inhibits his jumping, and who needs an endless supply of hugs to boost his tormented dormant spirit. Laura, a thin pink flat block that can bounce the other’s to new heights while dealing with the love in her heart for Chris. Claire, a blue superhero with the misleading power to float on water and have an extreme sense of resolution to aid. James, a green block that navigates the puzzles in a unique way where he sticks to the roof rather than the ground, wondering why differences are so differently viewed among the world with musings of hope and acceptance. Jon, a thin yellow stick that soars as high as his boisterous ego, and finally, Sarah, the double jumping mystical vat of weird declarations of intensions laced with power behind each thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each character has their own purpose and will need to be utilized, sometimes all at once in a puzzle that utilizes all of their abilities, sometimes with only one of the many wonderful personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disabled gamers won’t have a problem with the game at all because everything is very streamlined and plain, making for vast customization types, such as using the analog stick instead of the D pad to move characters. Even people who use one-handed controllers could play this game without assistance because the challenge lies within tacking new challenges onto the brain and not the limbs with a variety of jumping puzzles. The most complicated aspect of the game is making staircases with the characters in order to progress certain characters, but those scenarios happen sporadically and don’t hinder gameplay for very long. The more it’s required the more comfortable and natural it is to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Was Alone&lt;/em&gt; gives an all-encompassing experience that’s nestled inside a marvelously crafted world of stories, friends, and jumping. Disabled and non-disabled alike will easily remember the dashing characters and elegant level designs nestled inside of a very solid framework that stands tall and strong amongst bigger titles. The numerous memorabilia sprinkled throughout this game definitely show how even the simplest of implementations can be crafted with vivid vision into something that’s both mind blowing, and inclusive for the disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
