<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Tagged 'News', Sightless Scribbles</title>
  <subtitle>A fabulously gay blind author.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/posts/tags/news/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/" />
  <updated>2024-04-21T21:50:58Z</updated>
  <id>https://robertkingett.netlify.app/myblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Kingett</name>
    <email>kingettr@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Royalty statement 2023</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6540/" />
    <updated>2024-04-21T21:50:58Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6540/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’d like to show you how much I made for 2023 on my published books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, not so well, but you can read the table below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good thing I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/books/&quot;&gt;other books&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/writings/&quot;&gt;other writings&lt;/a&gt; out now, but still, sales matter. Money matters when making art of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really is that simple. If you want artists to keep making art, give them money and buy their work. I wish I had enough money to do more writing, but I simply don’t. I have to focus on living and paying bills and eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-breakdown&quot;&gt;The breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below breaks down &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/4305/&quot;&gt;Artificial Divide&lt;/a&gt; sales by outlet and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to give a hearty shoutout to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nevillepark.ca/&quot;&gt;Neville Park&lt;/a&gt; that assisted me with cleaning up the original PDF. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/4305/&quot;&gt;Artificial Divide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous year balance,-2.025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Divide,15.131,,,,,,,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TOTAL,13.106&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table that was here looked strange, visually speaking, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Artificial-Divide-Earnings-breakdown.html&quot;&gt;read the table here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two new books to buy from me.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6525/" />
    <updated>2024-03-25T20:44:36Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6525/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Surprise! I have news! I’m publishing something new!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it’s two things. One is a contribution to the anthology &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/6517/&quot;&gt;How to Save the World.&lt;/a&gt; I published a personal essay about my experiences becoming a penpal for prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is a book I’m super excited to share! &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/6522/&quot;&gt;Pass the Salt&lt;/a&gt; is a nonfiction collection of personal essays about the dating experience in Chicago in the 2010s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pass the Salt is funny, heartwarming, touching, and it’s just a snapshot of goodness. I hope you all really enjoy the book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best page to keep up with book formats and where to get it is on &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/posts/6522/&quot;&gt;this book landing page.&lt;/a&gt; As formats become available, I’ll put them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned because lots of interviews are coming about the book and my overall experiences. I’m so happy to finally release this out into the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Giving PeerTube a shot for podcast publishing.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6259/" />
    <updated>2023-12-03T22:00:04Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6259/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;PeerTube links are at the bottom of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It began, and ended, with a four hour YouTube ad wherein someone was talking to me like I was watching an actual video. The advertisement was presented in a way where it would look like a real video. It almost worked, until I remembered the title of the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I copied the video link, opened it up in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sulaiman-alqusaimi/accessible_youtube_downloader_pro/releases&quot;&gt;Accessible YouTube downloader,&lt;/a&gt; and watched the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then promptly deleted all my videos on YouTube. There was no way YouTube, Google, was going to get free content from me to train their AI thing. Many years late, unfortunately, because Google and other tech companies have been scraping data for training purposes long before AI became sentient and turned us all into toast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I’m not going to get rid of AI and AI scraping, but I can make tech bros aggravated in the process, which is all worth it, in my opinion. There’s no way I can completely stop tech bros from scraping my website, for example, because I’d have to constantly put up walls and, well, in the end, it’s not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can, though, use alternatives that are far better than YouTube, which is what I’m doing as of today. Because YouTube started to have a visceral war with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_blocking&quot;&gt;ad blockers&lt;/a&gt; in 2023, I went looking for alternatives that would give me the features I’d need as well as provide a great user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started off by looking at podcast hosts. The most accessible podcast host, and the best one, in my opinion, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pinecast.com/&quot;&gt;Pinecast,&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t support video. I wanted one podcast feed to publish both audio and video. &lt;a href=&quot;https://changelog.pinecast.com/&quot;&gt;Pinecast is amazing in every other way, though.&lt;/a&gt; It didn’t meet my needs so I went looking at PeerTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://joinpeertube.org/&quot;&gt;PeerTube is a Federated video platform.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PeerTube&quot;&gt;You can read about PeerTube this Wiki link.&lt;/a&gt; PeerTube has grown a lot, with many accessibility improvements, and the best part? It’s a video platform that also supports uploading audio files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could effectively publish both an audio and video podcast with just one platform. This is fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began by taking my time, looking at all the instances, and settled on an instance for now. I expect I’ll change instances again in the future, but for now, I’m happy where I’m at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow my PeerTube account from any other Fediverse project. Just copy my account link into your instance of choice and then start following me. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;My RSS feed can be found on my subscribe page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will this account be about? I really don’t know but it’s going to be all about me, obviously. Interviews, short stories, audio book excerpts, novellas in audio, clips of me at events, and everything else me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However you subscribe, I hope you check it out and share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ease of use, the links mentioned in the above post are below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find my PeerTube account at &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectra.video/a/weirdwriter&quot;&gt;@weirdwriter@spectra.video&lt;/a&gt;or &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/contact/&quot;&gt;on my contact page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectra.video/feeds/videos.xml?videoChannelId=4444&quot;&gt;Robert Kingett’s PeerTube RSS for podcast apps is here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;on my subscribe page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sensitivity reading to beat writers block</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/6081/" />
    <updated>2023-09-11T01:14:37Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/6081/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve got some good news, and, well, some coming soon news. But first, some good news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get started on the news, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/live/&quot;&gt;I have upcoming events! Come see me and say hi!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve grown into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/?p=5032&quot;&gt;quite formidable sensitivity reader,&lt;/a&gt; and even developmental editor somewhat. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/?p=5032&quot;&gt;The sensitivity reading is a way for me to support myself while I’m having writers block,&lt;/a&gt; which doesn’t happen often but there are days where I’m just like, I just want to lay in bed and watch old TV shows and movies because I’m low energy today! I’m actually getting a lot more work as a developmental editor and even a sensitivity reader than I initially thought. It’s great for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading others’ work actually gives me a boost in my own writing. It inspires me to read others’ work. I raised my rates too, among all companies and otherwise because I like having money. I like having a safety net. I of course, still write, but the sensitivity reading is helping to get inspiration as well as making connections. Again, it really does help with writer’s block!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/?p=1725/&quot;&gt;the expert witness work I do&lt;/a&gt; gives me a break, I hit the pitching mound. No bites yet on any of my completed novels or novellas but I do have good news to report about one of my previously published books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2017/04/07/off-the-grid-living-blind-without-the-internet/&quot;&gt;Off the Grid is getting new life!&lt;/a&gt; It’s being edited, and it’s got a new release date coming up! It’s going to have a new epilogue, and it will be edited for tighter and it’s going to be cleaned up even more. I was kind of self-publishing it for a while, but I honestly never want to self-publish again. It was a lot to manage, and I’d really much rather have a publisher handle it all. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2017/04/07/off-the-grid-living-blind-without-the-internet/&quot;&gt;Keep up with Off the Grid via this page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for what I’m up to? &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/ad/&quot;&gt;More audio description works&lt;/a&gt; in addition to the above. I’m still trying to maintain my distance from social media, in all forms. I mostly do automated posts on these platforms, directing people back to this website because this is my home now. This is my domain in my own space and so I want to have more people come to my little garden on the web. Gaze upon its ease to read. Gawk at the large font by default. Everything you see here has been by design. I mean, it doesn’t make sense to me why people bother making a website and then making the text small or making it harder to see the text because of a low contrast theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, a lot of updates are in absolute limbo, which is why I still rely on people to &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/donate/&quot;&gt;throw money at me while I hustle&lt;/a&gt; because publishing still doesn’t pay well, even after you hustle. Even so, I like bringing people stories and characters. I like bringing people characters I never got to see on the pages or even on screen before. That’s why I keep doing it, in the end, honestly, is because I’m stubborn, and, well, people like my work. Before I go, though,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;side note, I did discover &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovelyaudiobooks.info/duet-narration/&quot;&gt;the wonders of Duette audiobooks&lt;/a&gt; and, well, can we just say swoon? Swoon like a glittery romantic heart because I’m having far more fun with these narrations than anybody should. I’m enjoying them too much, both straight and gay relationships and pairings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I participated in the 2023 writers strike.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5958/" />
    <updated>2023-05-02T23:29:12Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5958/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The strike ended in late September, 2023. The writers on the picket lines fought very hard, and emerged with many gains for writers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgacontract2023.org/the-campaign/tentative-agreement&quot;&gt;Read the agreements and more provided by the WGA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgacontract2023.org/the-campaign/summary-of-the-2023-wga-mba&quot;&gt;Read the summary of the final 2023 negotiation here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theankler.com/p/adam-conover-wga-podcast&quot;&gt;Hear a podcast episode explaining the deals here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgacontract2023.org/updates&quot;&gt;See all past WGA Strike updates.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for me, this means I get to get back to work, for now! &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;Follow me on even more fun rides by subscribing however!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI might break the internet.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5949/" />
    <updated>2023-04-12T07:34:51Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5949/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Updates are at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2023/01/19/how-to-appreciate-humans/&quot;&gt;I’ve already written about so called AI,&lt;/a&gt; which isn’t really intelligent, before, but I’m in a mood, so buckle up for another rant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about content and consumption lately. Partly because, thanks to large language models other people are calling AI, I’ve been logging off the internet and eating older media more. It’s a fascinating time machine. I’ve been eating a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fictionpodcasts.com/&quot;&gt;fiction podcasts.&lt;/a&gt; I’ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://archiveofourown.org/tags/Ableism/works&quot;&gt;reading a lot of Disability fiction on Archive of Our Own.&lt;/a&gt; I know I’m not doing the productive thing in society’s eyes. More importantly, I’ve realized I’m starting to avoid the internet more. What prompted me to log off more started with a simple Google search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched for something on Google. Read a few articles, soon realized they were generated articles instead of written articles, tried to find some useful help to my query, discovered more generated articles, skimmed generated articles, sighed because these generated articles were flooding the top of multiple search engines, and then finally just said, fuck it, then listened to the original Star Wars audio drama after logging off the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people enjoy rolling their eyes at people that consume media, but don’t engage with it. But, like, I’m tired and don’t want to examine how this peace of media is misogynistic or ableist. I guess you could say that’s my main state of mind these days. I’m just tired. I’m exhausted by trying to understand generated text and or generated voices. I’ve enjoyed just appreciating works by humans instead of trying to decode stuff. I’ve even tried to read some generated fiction, written or narrated, and, as you can imagine, I’m never enjoying the work. I’m decoding it. I’m like a flawed computer that can’t compute what generated garbage is in front of me, so the best thing I can do is just, well, log off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I believe that’s the best way to make generated work fade away. I know it’s easier said than done, but the minute you know work is generated instead of created, just close the browser without leaving a comment or anything. Don’t leave an angry screed. That’s what the generator wants. They want reactions to their Word Roombas, written or narrated. I’ve never left a comment on a generated work and never will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to all who are wondering how I can tell it’s generated? Trust me, it’s beyond easy to spot, even if you human edit it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last post on the subject, unfortunately, played into the hype a little bit. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ouropinionsarecorrect.com/shownotes&quot;&gt;In an epic series by Our Opinions Are Correct,&lt;/a&gt; they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ouropinionsarecorrect.com/shownotes/2023/3/8/episode-125-silicon-valley-vs-science-fiction-part-i&quot;&gt;correctly point out that the hype is also fueled by, you guessed it, fearing humans will go extinct and be replaced by robots.&lt;/a&gt; Later in the series, they correctly examine how Silicon Valley doesn’t understand Science Fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peertube.dair-institute.org/videos/watch/205a27bc-c3aa-4a4d-93af-a7ec88a7b1a4&quot;&gt;This series of videos about deflating the AI Hype is also worth a watch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2023/01/19/how-to-appreciate-humans/&quot;&gt;While my last post was all, we should cherish humans,&lt;/a&gt; I’d like to examine some more thoughts about what the internet will be like with a flood of generated content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often hear from a lot of people now that they will, mostly, go back and read or watch older stuff they’ve appreciated because new choices are overwhelming. That’s how I feel about content these days. I don’t know why but I find that trying new books is far easier than trying new movies or TV shows. Maybe that’s because I’m a book lover. I also try a lot of fiction podcasts. But, like I said, I am more cautious and pickier online these days because generated content exhausts me to the point where, again, I say, fuck it, then just log off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps if I’m logging off again, maybe others will start logging off too? Maybe other people will write, offline, enjoying their fantasies where no generative model can scrape their words. Maybe others will log off and then call that person they were always too busy for because social media is a full time job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, seriously, social media is a full time job, and now, since large language models are flooding social media, I’ve found myself sighing and, once again, saying fuck it and logging off and absorbing human media more, no matter how problematic it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t adequately describe what I’m feeling. Maybe this is how the previous generations felt when the internet sprang onto the scene. Overwhelmed, tired, and just feeling powerless in a world that always wants to innovate without aiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, thousands of Blind people disagree with me. They think large language models will be brilliant for the internet because we won’t have to navigate complicated webpages. We can have a machine fetch the content for us. Usually, I find the answers never fully satisfy me, so I end up browsing the internet anyway, going down deep fandom rabbit holes and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to me logging off and consuming more. I don’t think I’m consuming. Others will disagree, but I believe I’m appreciating art. I’m leaving reviews on art I enjoy. I personally reach out to more writers to express how much I’ve enjoyed their story. It’s a vast difference from the sense of insurmountable boredom when I come across generated content. I know I can’t change the world, but I can do my part to make sure that these generators don’t get any part of my emotions. In fact, they won’t get feedback from me at all. Of course, it’s never about the act of creating for these generators, so they are probably not bothered by my silence, but I wonder how the internet will split if this keeps up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my predictions. The internet will split into two factions. An alcove of artists creating and sharing and experiencing, vs. The information super highway where everything is there to consume, consume, consume! I know where I’m headed. It’s going to be my artist alcove with others. Because, like I said before, generated content sucks, and beyond boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-small-updates&quot;&gt;Some small updates.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough about my thoughts, though! What am I up to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m on the hunt for a producer to take my screenplays and fiction podcast scripts. I’ve completed a bunch of scripts lately but haven’t found a home for any of them yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m trying &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.com/search?node=18580518011&amp;amp;searchProvider=Audible+Studios&amp;amp;ref=a_search_l1_catRefs_18&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=daf0f1c8-2865-4989-87fb-15115ba5a6d2&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=QQRV00N021DW4Y66SQ6F&amp;amp;pageLoadId=VFOKjmDpVQYgn7EJ&amp;amp;creativeId=9648f6bf-4f29-4fb4-9489-33163c0bb63e&quot;&gt;some romance audiobooks by Audible studios&lt;/a&gt; and really enjoying them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m pitching two romance novellas I wrote last year. No bites yet but I’ve been doing a lot of pitching previous things I’ve written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://socialaudiodescription.com/tag/robert-kingett/&quot;&gt;Creating more audio described content.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing Fanfiction. It’s private, and hidden, though. I just needed a space where I can write where my name isn’t attached to a thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a radio script in Fountain</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5913/" />
    <updated>2023-02-26T23:37:13Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5913/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aside from &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/writings/&quot;&gt;writing a bunch of books and short stories,&lt;/a&gt; I also &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/category/audio/&quot;&gt;write fiction podcast scripts.&lt;/a&gt; Luckily, the fiction podcast space isn’t so rigid as other industries, but still, there’s a few conventions I stick to in order to make everybody happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fountain.io/howto&quot;&gt;I write all of my fiction podcast scripts in Fountain.&lt;/a&gt; It’s free, portable, literally, and can be converted to almost anything, even Word files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sidebar, [try the &lt;a href=&quot;http://audio-drama.com/doku.php&quot;&gt;Audio Drama directory&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fictionpodcasts.com/&quot;&gt;Fiction Podcast directory.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t going to be a guide on Fountain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://fountain.io/syntax&quot;&gt;The Fountain syntax is the best place to learn how to write in Fountain.&lt;/a&gt; This is a testimonial as to what I do after the writing process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I’m blind, writing in plain text and then formatting it later is the best workflow. If you’re a visual learner, fountain isn’t the best thing for you. It’s plain text with special characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write text with any program, on any device, so why not take advantage of that portability?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenging bit comes in after I’ve written a fully-fledged script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libreoffice.org/download/download-libreoffice/&quot;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt; and even Word with some special autocorrect keys set up. For example, if I type, BBL, it transforms into, &amp;quot;I’ll be back later.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve added a bunch of autocorrect entries to help with capitalization and dashes and similar, so, for example, if I type, EXT/, it transforms into EXT. LOCATION — TIME and it does it in all caps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script is the easy part. I just open my program of choice and start typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;saving-in-fountain&quot;&gt;Saving in Fountain.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m all done, I make sure to save it as a .fountain extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a step-by-step on how to save a document as a fountain file, do the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish your document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Control, S, to bring up the save dialog box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to save the extension as a .fountain, dot Fountain, file. Instead of .ODT or .DOCX, save it as a .fountain file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;alternatively, you can save it as a plain text file and then change the extension name later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish your document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Control S, to bring up the save dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save it as a .TXT, dot T X T, file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to that TXT file you saved, hit shift F10, go down to, rename, and then change the extension to a .fountain file, dot fountain file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing and saving is the easy part. It’s the formatting and submitting process that’s the most time consuming, but even that can be streamlined a bit, especially in my case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t write in online editors like Google Docs because I’ve found it to be very slow and clunky, plus, it doesn’t have a robust autocorrect system the way Word and LibreOffice do. Their autocorrect system is very basic and most of the time doesn’t even work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Let’s get to the meat of this post, the formatting and conversion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formatting-a-script-using-pandoc-and-other-tools&quot;&gt;Formatting a script using Pandoc and other tools.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of tools can open, and read, fountain files, so, in most cases, you can save your script in a Fountain file extension and send that over. The producer can open the script in anything they want and it will come out nicely formatted. For those times when they insist on another format, though, that’s where the below comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though Fountain is very portable, not every podcast producer I’ve worked with could open Fountain files or even work with Fountain files, so I needed a way to convert the Fountain file into Word format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Wraparound/wrap&quot;&gt;There’s a fantastic open source tool to convert Fountain into HTML and PDF&lt;/a&gt; but it doesn’t support converting to Docx format. Plus, even if Word can open PDF files, it just isn’t a solution for everybody. PDF doesn’t work well with screen readers unless tagged, and, this is just my personal opinion, it’s very clunky, bulky, and, ironically isn’t all that portable in my opinion. I like lightweight documents and lightweight workflows and PDF just doesn’t cut it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, if your producer wants a PDF file, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Wraparound/wrap&quot;&gt;Wrapped will be everything you need&lt;/a&gt; and you can stop reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need a way to convert Fountain into Word, Pandoc can do this with a custom interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/installing.html&quot;&gt;get Pandoc for your operating system and install it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandoc can convert a whole bunch of things, so I’d encourage &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/getting-started.html&quot;&gt;reading the user’s guide to Pandoc if you want to explore other capabilities.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you need to download &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pandoc/pandoc-fountain&quot;&gt;this custom interpreter for Pandoc to convert Fountain to Docx files.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know how to download github repositories, expand the code, button, and then click on download as Zip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unzip the file, and then make sure to put your script into the unzipped folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Pandoc, navigate to where you unzipped the custom interpreter that also contains your script file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run this command, replacing the input and output file names as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pandoc -f fountain.lua --reference-doc fountain-ref.docx sample.fountain -o sample.docx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to know about the instructions, I don’t know why, but they didn’t work unless everything was on one line for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Windows code only works if you have it on one line, like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pandoc -f fountain.lua --reference-doc fountain-ref.docx sample.fountain -o sample.docx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it! While it’s not as quick or fluid as sending over a Fountain file directly, this will make sure your scripts look fabulous while writing everything in plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Books to understand me.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5805/" />
    <updated>2022-11-27T04:50:45Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5805/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the internet surprises me. While I typically find people that use social media unquestionably toxic, sometimes, the internet surprises me with something genuinely fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a post floating around that read, here’s seven books to get to know be by. The point is to have the books reveal aspects of someone’s personality while revealing other things about the person through, well, reading the books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looked genuinely fun. This, more than anything, shocked me. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/category/blog/&quot;&gt;I’ve written, numerous times before,&lt;/a&gt; about how I hate social media and believe people should learn how to email or text message someone again. All the same, this looked fun, so I figured I’d make a blog post detailing books to get to know me by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the below books reveal some aspect of how I think and feel. I’m not telling you which bits are in which book, that would be too easy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/books/&quot;&gt;the books by me&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/shorts/&quot;&gt;short stories by me,&lt;/a&gt; the below books reveal a lot about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-list-of-books&quot;&gt;The list of books.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/p/books/sick-kids-in-love-hannah-moskowitz/9196688?ean=9781682815052&quot;&gt;Sick Kids in Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hannah_Moskowitz&quot;&gt;Hannah Moskowitz&lt;/a&gt; (Author)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isabel has one rule: no dating.&lt;br&gt;
It’s easier–&lt;br&gt;
It’s safer–&lt;br&gt;
It’s better–&lt;br&gt;
–for the other person.&lt;br&gt;
She’s got issues. She’s got secrets. She’s got rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;br&gt;
But then she meets another sick kid.&lt;br&gt;
He’s got a chronic illness Isabel’s never heard of, something she can’t even pronounce. He understands what it means to be sick. He understands her more than her healthy friends. He understands her more than her own father who’s a doctor.&lt;br&gt;
He’s gorgeous, fun, and foul-mouthed. And totally into her.&lt;br&gt;
Isabel has one rule: no dating.&lt;br&gt;
It’s complicated–&lt;br&gt;
It’s dangerous–&lt;br&gt;
It’s never felt better–&lt;br&gt;
–to consider breaking that rule for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyman.com/books/schwa/&quot;&gt;The Schwa&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyman.com/books/&quot;&gt;Neal Shusterman.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say his clothes blend into the background, no matter where he stands. They say a lot of things about the Schwa, but one thing’s for sure: no one ever noticed him. Except me. My name is Antsy Bonano-and I was the one who realized the Schwa was “functionally invisible” and used him to make some big bucks. But I was also the one who caused him more grief than a friend should. So if you all just shut up and listen, I’ll tell you everything there is to know about the Schwa, from how he got his name, to what really happened with his mom. I’ll spill everything. Unless, of course, “the Schwa Effect” wipes him out of my brain before I’m done…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyman.com/books/bruiser/&quot;&gt;Bruiser by Neal Shusterman.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TENNYSON: &lt;br&gt;
Don’t get me started on The Bruiser. He was voted “Most Likely to Get the Death Penalty” by the entire school. He’s the kid no one knows, no one talks to, and everyone hears disturbing rumors about. So why is my sister, Brontë dating him? One of these days she’s going to take in the wrong stray dog, and it’s not going to end well.&lt;br&gt;
BRONTË:&lt;br&gt;
My brother has no right to talk about Brewster that way — no right to threaten him. There’s a reason why Brewster can’t have friends — why he can’t care about too many people.  Because when he cares about you, things start to happen. Impossible things that can’t be explained. I know because they’re happening to me.&lt;br&gt;
BREWSTER:&lt;br&gt;
Stealer of screams and thief of anguish,  I am a criminal, but you can’t see it, blinded by your own relief as my body becomes a battlefield in a war that can’t be won.  Will I be the bullet that ends your pain, or will you end mine?&lt;br&gt;
Award-winning author Neal Shusterman has crafted a chilling and unforgettable novel about the power of unconditional friendship, the complex gear work of a family, and the sacrifices we endure for the people we love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://walterdeanmyers.net/bibliography/awards/shooter/&quot;&gt;Shooter by Walter Dean Myers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cameron: “Deep inside, you know that whoever gets up in your face gets there because he knows you’re nothing, and he knows that you know it too.”&lt;br&gt;
Carla: “What I’m trying to do is to get by, not even get over, just get by.”&lt;br&gt;
Leonard: “I have bought a gaw-juss weapon. It lies beneath my bed like a secret lover, quiet, powerful, waiting to work its magic.”&lt;br&gt;
Statement of Fact: 17-year-old white male found dead in the aftermath of a shooting incident at Madison High School in Harrison County.&lt;br&gt;
Conclusion: Death by self-inflicted wound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidlubar.com/bpsfnl.html&quot;&gt;Sleeping Freshman Never Lie&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidlubar.com/mybooks.html&quot;&gt;David Lubar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting high school is never easy. Seniors take your lunch money. Girls you’ve known forever are suddenly beautiful and unattainable. And you can never get enough sleep. Could there be a worse time for Scott’s mother to announce she’s pregnant? Scott decides high school would be a lot less overwhelming if it came with a survival manual, so he begins to write down tips for his new sibling. Meanwhile, he’s trying his best to capture the attention of Julia, the freshman goddess. In the process, Scott manages to become involved in nearly everything the school has to offer. So while he tries to find his place in the confusing world of high school, win Julia’s heart, and keep his sanity, Scott will be recording all the details for his sibling’s—and your—enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kennyporpora.com/memoir/&quot;&gt;The Autumn Balloon by Kenny Porpora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every autumn, Kenny Porpora would watch his heartbroken mother scribble messages on balloons and release them into the sky above Long Island, one for each family member they’d lost to addiction. As the number of balloons grew, his mother fell deeper into alcoholism, drinking away her sorrows every night in front of the television, where her love of Regis Philbin provided a respite from the sadness around her.&lt;br&gt;
When their house was foreclosed upon, Kenny’s mother absconded with him and his beloved dog and fled for the Arizona desert, joining her heroin-addicted brother on a quixotic search for a better life. What followed was an outlaw adolescence spent in constant upheaval surrounded by bizarre characters and drug-addicted souls.&lt;br&gt;
In the wake of unspeakable loss, Kenny convinced a college to take a chance on him, and turned to the mentors, writers, and poets he found to rebuild the family he lost, and eventually graduated from the Ivy League with a new life.&lt;br&gt;
Porpora’s memoir is the story of a deeply dysfunctional but loving family, and follows his life from the chaos of his youth to his triumphs in the Ivy League. At times darkly comic, at times elegiac, The Autumn Balloon is a beautifully written testament to the irreplaceable bonds of family, even under the most trying circumstances, and one that marks the debut of an exciting new writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jameshowe.com/the-misfits&quot;&gt;The Misfits by James Howe.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kids who get called the worst names oftentimes find each other. That’s how it was with us. Skeezie Tookis and Addie Carle and Joe Bunch and me. We call ourselves the Gang of Five, but there are only four of us. We do it to keep people on their toes. Make ’em wonder. Or maybe we do it because we figure that there’s one more kid out there who’s going to need a gang to be a part of. A misfit, like us.&lt;br&gt;
Skeezie, Addie, Joe, and Bobby—they’ve been friends forever. They laugh together, have lunch together, and get together once a week at the Candy Kitchen to eat ice cream and talk about important issues. Life isn’t always fair, but at least they have each other—and all they really want to do is survive the seventh grade.&lt;br&gt;
That turns out to be more of a challenge than any of them had anticipated. Starting with Addie’s refusal to say the Pledge of Allegiance and her insistence on creating a new political party to run for student council, the Gang of Five is in for the ride of their lives. Along the way they will learn about politics and popularity, love and loss, and what it means to be a misfit. After years of getting by, they are given the chance to stand up and be seen—not as the one-word jokes their classmates have tried to reduce them to, but as the full, complicated human beings they are just beginning to discover they truly are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jameshowe.com/books-1/2017/5/4/bunnicula&quot;&gt;Bunnicula: A Rabbit-Tale of Mystery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BEWARE THE HARE! &lt;br&gt;
Is he or isn’t he a vampire? &lt;br&gt;
Before it’s too late, Harold the dog and Chester the cat must find out the truth about the newest pet in the Monroe household: a suspicious-looking bunny with unusual habits…and fangs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beckyalbertalli.com/simon-vs-the-homo-sapiens-agenda&quot;&gt;Simon vs. the Homo Sapiens Agenda&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beckyalbertalli.com/books&quot;&gt;Becky Albertalli.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixteen-year-old and not-so-openly gay Simon Spier prefers to save his drama for the school musical. But when an email falls into the wrong hands, his secret is at risk of being thrust into the spotlight. Now change-averse Simon has to find a way to step out of his comfort zone before he’s pushed out—without alienating his friends, compromising himself, or fumbling a shot at happiness with the most confusing, adorable guy he’s never met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonysnicket.com/books/&quot;&gt;The Series of Unfortunate Events by Lemony Snicket.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of great storytellers, from Dickens to Dahl, comes an exquisitely dark comedy that is both literary and irreverent, hilarious and deftly crafted. Never before has a tale of three likeable and unfortunate children been quite so enchanting, or quite so uproariously unhappy. &lt;br&gt;
Violet, Klaus, and Sunny Baudelaire are intelligent children. They are charming, and resourceful, and have pleasant facial features. Unfortunately, they are exceptionally unlucky.&lt;br&gt;
In the first two books alone, the three youngsters encounter a greedy and repulsive villain, itchy clothing, a disastrous fire, a plot to steal their fortune, a lumpy bed, a deadly serpent, a large brass reading lamp, a long knife, and a terrible odor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://megcabot.com/series/airhead/&quot;&gt;Airhead by Meg Cabot.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one cares what’s inside.&lt;br&gt;
EM WATTS IS GONE.&lt;br&gt;
Emerson Watts didn’t even want to go to the new SoHo Stark Megastore grand opening. But someone needed to look out for her sister Frida, whose crush, British heartthrob Gabriel Luna, would be singing and signing autographs there—along with the newly appointed Face of Stark, teen supermodel sensation Nikki Howard.&lt;br&gt;
How was Em to know that disaster would strike, changing her—and life as she’d known it—forever? One devastating accident later, and Em Watts, always the tomboy, never the party princess, is no longer herself. Literally.&lt;br&gt;
Now getting her best friend Christopher to notice that she’s actually a girl is the least of Em’s problems.&lt;br&gt;
But what Em’s pretty sure she’ll never be able to accept might just turn out to be the one thing that’s going to make her dream come true.&lt;br&gt;
NIKKI HOWARD IS HERE TO STAY&lt;br&gt;
It’s what’s outside that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://catalog.loc.gov/vwebv/holdingsInfo?searchId=5868&amp;amp;recPointer=0&amp;amp;recCount=25&amp;amp;searchType=1&amp;amp;bibId=14537887&quot;&gt;Running With Scissors by Augusten Burroughs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the true story of a boy whose mother (a poet with delusions of Anne Sexton) gave him away to be raised by her psychiatrist, a dead-ringer for Santa and a lunatic in the bargain. Suddenly, at age twelve, Augusten Burroughs found himself living in a dilapidated Victorian in perfect squalor. The doctor’s bizarre family, a few patients, and a pedophile living in the backyard shed completed the tableau. Here, there were no rules, there was no school. The Christmas tree stayed up until summer, and Valium was eaten like Pez. And when things got dull, there was always the vintage electroshock therapy machine under the stairs. It is at turns foul and harrowing, compelling and maniacally funny, but above all, it chronicles an ordinary boy’s survival under the most extraordinary circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brandonlgtaylor.com/books&quot;&gt;Real Life by Brandon Taylor.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everything about Wallace is at odds with the Midwestern university town where he is working uneasily toward a biochem degree. An introverted young man from Alabama, black and queer, he has left behind his family without escaping the long shadows of his childhood. For reasons of self-preservation, Wallace has enforced a wary distance even within his own circle of friends–some dating each other, some dating women, some feigning straightness. But over the course of a late-summer weekend, a series of confrontations with colleagues, and an unexpected encounter with an ostensibly straight, white classmate, conspire to fracture his defenses while exposing long-hidden currents of hostility and desire within their community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Some tips for Blind Audio Description writers</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5732/" />
    <updated>2022-10-26T21:24:27Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5732/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before I worked in the audio description industry and joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://adcomrade.wordpress.com/about/&quot;&gt;an audio description collective,&lt;/a&gt; I consumed &lt;a href=&quot;https://adp.acb.org/ad.html&quot;&gt;audio description&lt;/a&gt; daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those not familiar with audio description, it’s painting a picture with words for those that are unable to look at a screen, including Blind and visually impaired people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adp.acb.org/samples.html&quot;&gt;There are many samples you can watch to get a sense of how audio description works.&lt;/a&gt; It’s painting a picture between natural pauses in the soundtrack of a production. It’s also great for podcasts and radio listeners, too. Audio description can benefit so many people, including sighted people that are unable to look at a screen because they are busy or because they are listening to an audio only podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio description is very different from closed captioning. It’s an art as well as a science. It isn’t just about interpreting what someone sees, it’s crafting a visual interpretation to go along with the ebb and flow of the scene as well as the whole production. Up until now, Blind and visually impaired people rarely had opportunities to shape and craft audio description. That’s changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theadna.org/credits/&quot;&gt;Blind and visually impaired people are audio description narrators, engineers, Quality Control specialists,&lt;/a&gt; people that are basically script editors that make sure the script makes sense to the intended audience, and writers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://theadna.org/credits/&quot;&gt;Blind and visually impaired people are getting involved in the making of audio description.&lt;/a&gt; I’m here to talk about some tips I’ve learned as a Blind audio description writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a brief rundown of my audio description work, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://adcomrade.wordpress.com/tag/robert-kingett/&quot;&gt;my work with Social Audio Description&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/?p=4348&quot;&gt;see my work on other films and TV shows including those found on popular streaming services.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ad-tools-i-use&quot;&gt;The AD tools I use.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use all of the below tools when crafting audio description scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Sheets, mainly because it can export to CSV beautifully so I can open it in my text editor of choice for editing or writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgbh.org/foundation/services/ncam/cadet&quot;&gt;CADET&lt;/a&gt; for timing the AD in points and exit points. I don’t write with this program but I do take notes with this. Instead of writing the AD, I put notes about what to describe with timecodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;, for writing the actual AD script after timecodes have been created in another program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/julbean/describealign&quot;&gt;describealign&lt;/a&gt; for testing out AD audio files with video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rkingett/ADConvert&quot;&gt;Some Python scripts to convert scripts into many formats at once&lt;/a&gt; to convert many subtitle files to CSV and other formats so I can share them with my team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pablobernabeu.github.io/applications-and-dashboards/vtt-transcription-app/&quot;&gt;Convert captions to plain text.&lt;/a&gt; Useful if someone just wants the text and no timecodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opentogethertube.com/&quot;&gt;Open Together Tube&lt;/a&gt; for watching videos with other people at the same time, remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordhippo.com/&quot;&gt;WordHippo&lt;/a&gt; for looking for similar words or definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kyle95wm/audiodescription-tools&quot;&gt;this set of scripts by a low vision AD writer converts an SRT file to outputs&lt;/a&gt; depending on the DAW, Digital Audio Workstation, your team is using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ad-writing-process&quot;&gt;The AD writing process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My process for writing audio description is very involved. I first watch the production several times taking copious amounts of notes on sounds I hear as well as key sounds conveyed by the production. Key sounds could include music tempo, noticeable background sounds, the cadence of the music for a particular scene, and more. If a script is available, I read the full script before watching the production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgbh.org/foundation/services/ncam/cadet&quot;&gt;CADET&lt;/a&gt; to insert timestamps into the script. I take notes with this program by inserting notes to myself on how to describe and what to describe in the spaces where it wants me to put a description. I don’t write my AD in this program because I love working with lightweight text editors and this app is way to bloated to do any writing, but it’s fantastic for exporting and importing files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can actually use any captioning software to create the AD timecodes, I just haven’t found a plain text oriented program that works with keyboard commands, and is screen reader friendly, and exports to text based formats other than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgbh.org/foundation/services/ncam/cadet&quot;&gt;CADET.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_subtitle_editors&quot;&gt;None of these subtitle editors&lt;/a&gt; are fully accessible to the blind that I’ve tried so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wgbh.org/foundation/services/ncam/cadet&quot;&gt;I use Cadet to make the timecodes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I have my timecodes and notes, I export it to a plain text file and an SRT file, something that can work with my favorite text editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I have my AD script in a timestamped text file, I then utilize sighted assistants to tell me various clues about the indicated scene. Because my script is already in aSRT or text file, no conversion needed. Just write, and save, as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then convert that plain text file or SRT to a CSV file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When writing, I always pull from a diverse roster of assistants I handpicked for this particular task. These people are different races, genders, sexualities, and otherwise. It’s important for me to get at least four differing perspectives on a scene or production. I’ll sometimes use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aira.io/&quot;&gt;Aira&lt;/a&gt; when none of my assistants are available, but I lean on my assistants first. They know me better. They know, generally, what I’m looking for and they have a more general idea of how I’m going to ask the dozens upon dozens of questions I’ve prepared ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask my assistants these questions I’ve crafted based on the sounds I hear, the accents I hear, the background noises I hear, and otherwise. I don’t let just any random person be my audio description assistant. I want my audio description assistants to have some key skills in place before I begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my criteria for audio description assistants are,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have to read a lot. This helps with explaining what they mean if something is unclear. They don’t need to be writers in order to internalize how to drill down and describe a scene. As people read books, they pick up phrases and that helps them expand upon concepts and descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need to know film terms. I like using film terms in my audio description and I want someone that knows what a cut is, and I want someone that knows what a fade in is versus a cut to a scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need to work in the fashion industry or at least love fashion. I want someone that can tell me the difference between a floral print dress versus a knee-high skirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For watching these videos simultaneously, syncing up videos, I use two methods. &lt;a href=&quot;https://opentogethertube.com/&quot;&gt;I use Open Together Tube&lt;/a&gt; or I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/201362153-Sharing-your-screen-or-desktop-on-Zoom&quot;&gt;Zoom’s share feature.&lt;/a&gt; I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://ninite.com/klitecodecs/&quot;&gt;Media Player Classic&lt;/a&gt; to get timestamps for videos. If MPC isn’t working for any reason, I will switch to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.videolan.org/vlc/&quot;&gt;VLC Media Player.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write all my scripts in the CSV format or a plain text file or an SRT file in my favorite text editor of choice. Depending on the scope of the project I’ll upload that text file to Google sheets and share it so people can download the sheet in their format of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all the questions are answered to my satisfaction, I’ll sometimes call Aira if I want to have an outside opinion, but usually, my team at Social Audio Description is more than willing to jump in to be that one outside pair of eyes, to ensure my notes align with someone that isn’t close to the production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adcomrade.wordpress.com/team/&quot;&gt;My team at Social Audio Description&lt;/a&gt; is also more than willing to be my audio description assistants for SADC projects when my usual roster is in short supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep track of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/wotd/feed/rss2&quot;&gt;this word of the day RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordhippo.com/&quot;&gt;WordHippo&lt;/a&gt; if I want to find a similar word&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all notes are complete, I then just write the audio description script. That’s it. There’s nothing more to it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/writings/&quot;&gt;My writing background helps a lot with this task.&lt;/a&gt; It sure does come in handy when I need to reach for a verb or an adjective that’s one syllable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though my writing background helps me immensely with this task there are several things I’ve had to learn as an audio description writer. I’d like to lay down some tips and tricks I’ve learned in the hopes that these tips and tricks help you in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-extra-tips-and-resources&quot;&gt;Some extra tips and resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read your audio description script out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve done this a few times before sending it off to the narrator. I’ve read my own scripts out loud to myself several times to ensure the timing fits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, one word is better than two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If possible, and if you’re crunched for time, one word that appears to be a longer word might fit better than the two shorter words you were initially going for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to imagine your narrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was starting out, I’d keep trying to envision the narrator before writing. I’d imagine a narrator’s voice before even beginning to write and that left me thinking I should write less because I believed my imaginary narrator would speak slowly. Try not to worry about the narrator. It isn’t your job to worry about how the narrator will sound. Be cognizant of the complicated words you’re giving them, but they have their own part to play. You should write to your satisfaction first. If adjustments need to be made later based on the narrator, that’s far easier to do than adding to your script because you were imagining a narrator and not writing enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to use a thesaurus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use many tools at my disposal. I have a Word of the Day alert sent to me every morning through my smart speakers. My biggest tool when reaching for a word is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordhippo.com/&quot;&gt;an online tool called WordHippo.&lt;/a&gt; It helps in my fiction writing too. WordHippo takes some getting used to with a screen reader but it’s well worth it. I love this tool and use it daily to craft my writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to hide your writing voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People will try to tell you that audio description shouldn’t be novelized or subjective. Films and other kinds of art will never be objective, so why should you try and hide your writing voice? Of course, audio description isn’t a novel, but don’t be afraid to inject some of your personality into your audio description scripts. If you want to novelize by using adjectives like beseechingly, angrily, furiously, ghastly, go for it. Your goal isn’t to please everybody. your goal is to provide audio description that’s true to you. You’re providing a service, yes, but your script is your script, and people are free to like it or hate it. Diversity in audio description is never a bad thing. Obviously, remember who you’re providing a service for, though. This service isn’t for you exclusively. It’s for your Blind and visually impaired audience but you can make your scripts your own way. People are free to have their beloved audio description writers and their most hated. That’s what advances conversations. Advancing dialog is always a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Falling into romance writing.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5715/" />
    <updated>2022-10-17T19:58:50Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5715/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I’m going to be linking to a lot of books, so make sure you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libraryextension.com/&quot;&gt;the library extension&lt;/a&gt; installed! It will help you save your wallet and find these books at libraries near you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a tragic event can leave you evaluating your whole presence on this earth. Unfortunately, after almost three years of COVID free life, I contracted COVID—19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t wish this on my worst enemy! The short version is that I’m coming around, with a lot of support and members of my Found Family watching over me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was in quarantine, it gave me a lot of time to look back at &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/shorts/&quot;&gt;the previous fiction I’ve written&lt;/a&gt; and really try to determine the kind of fiction I want to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, I’ve been avoiding romance because I didn’t believe I could write romance. I didn’t think I’d do well in romance. But, after a closer examination by my beta readers, romance seems to be the genre I’m just naturally comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s ironic, but I didn’t read a lot of romance. I read a lot of YA which had a romance element in it, but I didn’t read anything in the romance genre hardly. So, I figured the best thing to do would be to try some romance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://lgbtqreads.com/tag/mm/&quot;&gt;many M/M titles that captured my interest&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to try some minority romance writers. I started off by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.com/blog/black-voices-in-romance&quot;&gt;reading this audiobook roundup of romance titles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One author I seem to be enjoying a lot is &lt;a href=&quot;https://kennedyryanwrites.com/audiobooks/&quot;&gt;Kennedy Ryan.&lt;/a&gt; Her &lt;a href=&quot;https://libro.fm/search?q=Grip&amp;amp;searchby=series&amp;amp;sortby=series_asc&quot;&gt;Grip series&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.com/series/Grip-Audiobooks/B07477ZMQG?ref=a_pd_Flow-A_c1_series_1&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=df6bf89c-ab0c-4323-993a-2a046c7399f9&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=91E3Y9B6PJCEHH9E39RM&quot;&gt;alternative link Grip series on Audible&lt;/a&gt;) snagged me from the moment I finished, &lt;a href=&quot;https://libro.fm/audiobooks/9781541477599-flow-the-grip-prequel&quot;&gt;Flow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://kennedyryanwrites.com/hoopsebook/&quot;&gt;her Hoops series,&lt;/a&gt; but I’ll get there. I first want to explore some &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovelyaudiobooks.info/romance-books-about-disability/&quot;&gt;romance books featuring Disabled characters.&lt;/a&gt; Speaking of Disabled characters,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2018, I published &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2018/11/20/a-deserving-conference-by-robert-kingett/&quot;&gt;my first romance story called A Deserving Conference.&lt;/a&gt; It could be classified as dark romance, but it does have a HFN ending. Happy for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2018/11/20/a-deserving-conference-by-robert-kingett/&quot;&gt;A Deserving Conference&lt;/a&gt; and I am now expanding it. I’m also taking &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2020/05/04/community-of-magic-pens/&quot;&gt;Pointy Chances, found in Community of Magic Pens,&lt;/a&gt; and expanding that as well into its own book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to read more romance, I’m noticing that not many romance books feature Blind characters, let alone disabled characters. It’s going to be especially challenging for me because I’m actually very new to the genre and don’t particularly like writing sex scenes due to my own trauma, but I hope that you’ll be willing to come along this journey with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to support my work in the meantime, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/donate/&quot;&gt;donate to me in a variety of ways.&lt;/a&gt; I’d also encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://rk.groups.io/g/portfolio/join&quot;&gt;sign up to my mailing list&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/team/&quot;&gt;join my street team.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Back to feeling lovely with all my book boyfriends!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>About me in my own words.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5655/" />
    <updated>2022-06-23T09:42:02Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5655/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This originally appeared in Bold Blind Beauty in June 2020. The website appears to have shut down so I am printing this essay here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;born-a-miracle&quot;&gt;Born A Miracle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been somewhat of a miracle baby, or person, I guess you could say now. I fully embrace it, though, and yes, even the inspirational label that gets placed on me sometimes. I embrace it all because I just simply don’t have time to quibble over a slightly incorrect label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My miracle journey started in 1989 where I was a premature baby. It’s so wild, because my birth certificate says six ounces. I was born in September. I have no idea when I was actually supposed to be born, but I came out defying all odds from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born with Retinopathy of prematurity (ROP), as well as cerebral palsy. I wasn’t supposed to walk. I wasn’t supposed to talk either. My mobility was supposed to be very limited throughout my whole life. And, to a certain extent, that’s true now that I’m older, but back then, I did walk, and I did talk. I overcame so much at such a young age. I still had communication issues though. I stammered badly as a kid and still do. Which, ironically, is why I enjoy and embrace writing so feverishly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-his-terms&quot;&gt;On His Terms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born in New York but grew up in Saint Augustine FL. I attended the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind and that’s how my path to adaptive technology and accessibility consulting came to be, but more on that later. I’m probably one of the very few kids that actively refused mainstream school. I rejected it firmly. I hated the thought of attending a mainstream school. I knew I was getting the adaptive technology and mobility training that would help me later on in life. I didn’t want to waste my time advocating for everything under the sun. I knew that advocacy would come later, certainly, in college, so I wanted my high school to be as painless and as inclusive to my visual impairment as humanly possible and I just didn’t see that in a mainstream school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that society saw me as another worldly being that wasn’t worth nurturing as a disabled person, so I perceived mainstream school to just be an academic hassle. It probably would have done wonders for my social life, but I didn’t care about having an active social life when I was younger. I also didn’t want to be around sighted people unless it was on my own terms because, I believed, that my academics would suffer because I’d be trying to develop social justifications. I thought my energy would be wiped because I’d have to constantly demonstrate to sighted people that I’m worthy of existing and taken seriously. At a blind school, disabilities didn’t factor into my acceptance so I could focus on my education without worrying about social norms or fitting in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason why a big part of that unwillingness to fight for a mainstream education was so strong is because I was getting a very accessible education. I also was just trying to get through the day, and to my eventual long-term goal of becoming influential. Even if it was silent influence, I wanted to actively chip away at the social barriers disabled people face on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-scrapper-to-success&quot;&gt;From Scrapper To Success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My home life wasn’t that great. I was abused, both physically, mentally, emotionally, and otherwise. My mother, who was a single parent, didn’t know how to deal with her own daemons so she took them out on me. She was a heavy drinker and, yes, there would be beatings. I often went hungry, so I absolutely empathize with someone when they tell people they don’t know what real hunger feels like. People will never fully grasp it, I realized, so I just had to survive. Get out. Become as successful as I could possibly be and hope I make a small difference in the world, even if it’s educating someone about blindness or starts a chain reaction that makes things more accessible for many in my generation and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I developed a strong sense of advocacy in my teen years. I’ve never been good at giving a punchy media bite that goes viral or gets people talking. I knew I’d never be in the spotlight however, I knew my strength was in planning and strategic implementations. Oh, and trickle-down advocacy—chain reaction advocacy, as I call it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m very career-driven, and very focused, which is probably why I’m still single. I’m very proudly gay and or queer. I use those words interchangeably to describe my sexuality. I’m definitely not bisexual though, I’m very much gay. But, often, the men I’m attracted to are sighted and have no idea how to keep up with my career drive. That’s something that will, eventually, slow down I’m sure as I get even older, but for now, I’m very focused. I find the idea of romance and love is just something that I will find when it finds me, and grabs hold of me. That’s ironic because I’m an extremely romantic person. I’m very empathetic but extremely strong, personality-wise. I guess you could say I’m a mashup of imperfections that changes people’s lives in small ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path-to-journalism&quot;&gt;The Path To Journalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advocacy started when I created the first-ever newspaper for the blind at FSDB. That proved to me that I could give people chances and opportunities if I just kept being persistent. As a result, well, I’m Very forward-thinking and I’m a proud feminist and trans ally. I knew I had the power to change lives through journalism and fiction, so I began writing. Fiction, advocacy journeys, telling people’s stories. I find that very few people have media literacy skills. I read, constantly. I even read mainstream news everybody likes to rag on so much, but again, very few people just simply don’t know how the media works in general, which is why I don’t get into small fights online about mainstream media and agendas and biases and otherwise. It’s all trite ignorance and a complete waste of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My writing eventually created the Accessible Netflix Project, which actually got Netflix to provide audio description platform-wide wherever possible. This was a huge accomplishment, but my work isn’t over with. My real love is books. Especially diverse books, and audiobooks, and the publishing industry. I’m working to eventually make it so that seeing blindness in fiction is common while continuing to be a very strong ally to my fellow minorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;unicorns-cookies-and-education&quot;&gt;Unicorns, Cookies &amp;amp; Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always find it really weird when someone asks me what my hobbies are. My hobbies are extremely plain and ordinary. Like, who doesn’t like listening to music and watching TV shows with audio description? I know a few people who don’t like reading, but I just imagine them as very confused unicorns and continue loving books and literature. I read, certainly. I watch very dark comedy. I listen to boy bands. I steal rainbow tinged cookies from unsuspecting glittering cats in my spare time. I’m so done with being normal. It’s overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically speaking, my career path has never been regular, either. I dropped out of college, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/books/&quot;&gt;published several books,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/shorts/&quot;&gt;wrote short stories,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/writings/&quot;&gt;wrote nonfiction&lt;/a&gt; that makes people laugh, did accessibility consulting, and, finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/resume/&quot;&gt;wear a lot of other hats as well.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take this opportunity to tell all the readers to stay in school. Seriously. I think education is the most important facet in someone’s life. Encourage reading. Encourage creativity, because that’s what truly makes the world go round.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Updates only and author harassment</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5541/" />
    <updated>2022-03-07T03:10:11Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5541/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2021/10/11/different-literary-activism/&quot;&gt;the post Different Literary Activism.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading a Trans and Disability inclusive Harry Potter fanfiction called &lt;a href=&quot;https://archiveofourown.org/works/16269131&quot;&gt;Basilisk Eyes.&lt;/a&gt; I took a break from the audiobook, bookmarked &lt;a href=&quot;https://archiveofourown.org/series/1591198&quot;&gt;another Blind Harry Potter series,&lt;/a&gt; and finally just turn my once active social media accounts, including Twitter, into updates only accounts. I’ll still post to social media using automation tools and human managers, but I won’t engage with users anymore. The final straw was actually two incidents I learned about in one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-men-scenario&quot;&gt;The Men scenario&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first incident involved a book synopsis for an upcoming book many people haven’t read yet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myfloridahouse.gov/Sections/Bills/billsdetail.aspx?BillId=76545&quot;&gt;Just weeks after many bad things happened in politics for LGBT+ authors,&lt;/a&gt; in addition to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/10/29/schools-are-banning-my-book-queer-kids-need-queer-stories/&quot;&gt;having books by Trans writers banned in multiple states,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sannewman/status/1500177352420175874&quot;&gt;Sandra Newman announced a new book on Twitter.&lt;/a&gt; It’s called the Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve since read the book and choose to support another book instead. In truth, &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250794642/manhunt&quot;&gt;Manhunt was far more interesting to me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still choose not to partake in any public outrage. I am a quiet rage kind of person. I like to build a literary world by sharing other books I enjoy rather than just criticizing an author. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2020/09/25/on-the-attack-helicopter-story-by-isabel-fall/&quot;&gt;The Isabelle Fall incident&lt;/a&gt; will always haunt me, and it’s made me never take part in any public outrage campaign, even if it appears justified anger. I’m always fascinated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kacencallender.com/post/wip-social-media-and-mental-health&quot;&gt;how much authors receive online harassment, though.&lt;/a&gt; Ultimately, it’s taking justified anger at the inadequate and severely broken system and directing it towards individuals. Producing better art is more powerful, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, every reply, share, or retweet, keeps social media going. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/social-media-harassment-platforms/&quot;&gt;Twitter, and all other social media including Instagram, is designed for you to be a jerk online.&lt;/a&gt; I’d much rather starve social media of engagement and promote works I like, rather than tweet about books I hate. More importantly, I’d rather share other marginalized authors work if I love it anyway, because building a better network of books is better than just eliminating the problematic ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also why &lt;a href=&quot;https://bannedbooks.library.cmu.edu/directory-of-books/&quot;&gt;I read every banned book, ever.&lt;/a&gt; Even books that are classified as problematic or hateful. The common argument is that these are hateful thoughts and ideas, so why even entertain them. The reason why I read problematic books of all kinds is to make me a better activist, and it allows me to challenge my own privileges. I don’t share every book I read. Problematic books allow me to engage with and undo my privileges. By reading diverse art as well as problematic art, I’m unravelling multiple facets of my privileges. Nobody online deserves access to that process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;brandon-s-kickstarter&quot;&gt;Brandon’s Kickstarter.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though that outrage made me tired, the above incident wasn’t the final straw that finally made me cut the social media cord. What did it for me was &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/culture/2022/03/brandon-sanderson-kickstarter-criticism-why-writers-are-upset-about-his-record-setting-campaign.html&quot;&gt;outrage and then harassment over Brandon Sanderson successfully, independently, raising money&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/dragonsteel/surprise-four-secret-novels-by-brandon-sanderson?ref=ap1c6r&quot;&gt;a book related Kickstarter.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admit, I don’t understand the outrage and harassment for this one. I understand the criticism, I don’t understand the outrage. An author that’s cultivated a strong fanbase independently raised money for a book series without one of the big five publishers taking a cut. I don’t read a lot of Brandon Sanderson books. I dip in and out. The only book series I’ve consistently enjoyed of his, so far, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brandonsanderson.com/alcatraz-vs-the-evil-librarians-series/&quot;&gt;the Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians series.&lt;/a&gt; I devoured all of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.graphicaudio.net/alcatraz-series-set.html&quot;&gt;the Graphic Audio versions&lt;/a&gt; of the books in a few days. The outrage for this incident, though, appears to be points more people should be making to the wider publishing industry, not an author that’s publishing books on their own, with money raised through independent means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outrage has a few key points to it. The outrage says A financially privileged author such as Brandon Sanderson shouldn’t be making that amount of money when there are so many marginalized authors struggling to get published. There’s also some side outrage about the new book series being racist and transphobic and bigoted, but the main criticism is more valid and worth talking about. The side outrage is a footnote to the main outrage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whatever.scalzi.com/2022/03/01/very-quick-thoughts-on-brandon-sandersons-mega-kickstarter/#comment-909107&quot;&gt;John Scalzi also weighed in.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the criticism is valid, I still don’t understand the outrage. The outrage says things that definitely need to be repeated but it needs to be directed at the publishing industry as a whole. Not an author publishing books through Kickstarter. In truth, this should send a message to readers to start supporting more independent authors and independent presses trying to raise funds. This should send a message to publishing, that, actually, publishing should start treating it’s editors and literary agents better along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Xsx6rKJtafa8f_prlYYD3zRxaXYVDaPXbasvt_iA2vA/htmlview?pru=AAABcrmKYhg*ATaByrm8IcfLO57THcAKFA#gid=1798364047&quot;&gt;treating underrepresented and mid list authors better.&lt;/a&gt; It should send a message to publishing that valuing authors is more important than publishing wants to believe. Brandon Sanderson raised money, on Kickstarter, using just his readership and his fanbase. That’s good. Supporting marginalized and underrepresented authors is good. Both can be valid. Brandon’s Kickstarter has only grown. It’s surpassed its goal, and I don’t foresee anything bad happening to all those pledges anytime soon. So, I’d rather talk about what this means for publishing, and, in particular, what that looks like from Disabled writers like me. Firstly, a lot of people are cheering that this is going to shake up the publishing industry, and those old people will be dragged, kicking and screaming, to a new way of arranging pre orders and this will become the new way of buying books, probably! I’ve often found a lot of people that are saying this often don’t work in the industry, or just salivate at anything antiestablishment no matter the accelerationist view and ignoring or refusing to think about harm reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from many young people really wanting to work directly inside the publishing industry, the industry is, indeed, changing. It’s changing because workers are asking smarter questions such as why do literary agents have to take three jobs? Why is it that a junior executive never seems to grow with the company? These are good questions that more should be asking. One step towards meaningful progress is valid, smart, questions. I can guarantee you a lone Kickstarter isn’t the progressive shakeup many people believe it to be. I’m afraid, though, it will have an impact on marginalized authors, but not in the way many believe. First though, I’d like to draw your attention to a few folks that are far smarter than I am about the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/printrunpodcast/episode-148all-the-wrong-lessons&quot;&gt;Print Run did a whole episode about what the Kickstarter means for publishing.&lt;/a&gt; While I agree with them, I’d like to tackle a few angles outside of the scope of that podcast episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Let’s examine success in the publishing world. To be successful, an author needs to cultivate, and keep, a loyal readership. Publishing wants readers because publishing wants to know that advance they pay authors will be recouped before they take a chance on their next book. Even hate reads are still reads. The worst kind of feedback an author can get is total silence. If nobody is talking about the book, that book isn’t getting read by many people. There’s a whole subsect of readers that sincerely want that worthy test to go away, and have works exist regardless of readership, which is a valuable direction we should be headed in, but I consider that to be a utopia we will never reach. So, for now, Let’s say progress means less value on a prepackaged audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, workers in the industry have been publishing different kinds of stories. Sure, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Xsx6rKJtafa8f_prlYYD3zRxaXYVDaPXbasvt_iA2vA/htmlview?pru=AAABcrmKYhg*ATaByrm8IcfLO57THcAKFA#gid=1798364047&quot;&gt;diverse authors don’t get paid nearly a fraction as status quo authors,&lt;/a&gt; but that’s a symptom of a far bigger problem. Publishing wants to just take advantage of pre packaged audiences rather than helping authors build audiences organically. Basically, publishing takes less risks because publishing has to do less work by taking less risks. This is why an author is never guaranteed a publisher, even if their first book sells. It’s not good enough, the second book doesn’t get published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because an author has a literary agent, which doesn’t mean that agent will be able to sell their book. Agents have all the connections, sure. At the end of the day, they are not the decision makers for what books get published. They are an author advocate. Their job is to stand alongside the author and guide them through this industry. They will give knowledge and tools how to thrive in the industry, but they don’t publish books. They are an author go between for key editors. This is often why agents are hungry for more diverse books. They are not risk adverse. They know diversity sells, and that audiences are everywhere if you just look hard enough. They explain to publishers why they love your book and why the publishing industry should take a chance on it. The agent and the author are a team. This is what makes them so valuable to authors that get agents. Agents and authors work in tandem on their careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with an agent, publishing is still risk adverse. Publishers don’t always accept a book an agent is gushing about on the phone call they’re having. Status quo authors don’t have this added barrier. Because the perception of Trans, Black, Disabled, indigenous, and or LGBT+ authors is so low, this battle of getting someone to even consider our work triples in magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/printrunpodcast/episode-148all-the-wrong-lessons&quot;&gt;Print Run posits that the publishing executive’s will take Brandon’s Kickstarter success the wrong way and make it harder, not easier, for diverse authors to be included at the table.&lt;/a&gt; As a Disabled, and gay, writer myself, I also fear that publishing will expect Kickstarter campaigns to do well before future contracts can even be imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TVdZ018gsRw&quot;&gt;Brandon finding, and funding, publishing Kickstarters&lt;/a&gt; is the best thing he could have done with some of the money he raised. His Kickstarter has implications for marginalized authors. I fear his Kickstarter will become a jumping off point for publishers forcing marginalized writers to prove that a built in audience will arrive, prepackaged, with the author so that the publisher doesn’t have to do any work to help authors build an audience. Publishers are supposed to aid writers in building an organic audience. This Kickstarter gave more incentive for publishers to accept less from literary agents and expect more from writers if an agent pitches them a manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literary agents are very good author advocates, which is why I continue to seek traditional publishing avenues. I’m also very glad that Brandon Sanderson understands his privileges and works to lift other writers up in multiple ways. The online outrage, though, doesn’t even come close to talking about the actual barriers that are beyond Brandon’s Kickstarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anger drives social media engagement. Social media anger also stifles creativity and eats up my time. I’ve decided to just stop giving social media what it wants. Engagement. I now engage with art more, participate in many cooperatives, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/progress/&quot;&gt;do lots of writing and reading offline,&lt;/a&gt; and work on improving myself and my ideas of an inclusive society offline. I listen to people more as well when they approach me to tell me something. &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2017/04/07/off-the-grid-living-blind-without-the-internet/&quot;&gt;In my first memoir, I was very happy to come back online after a month without it.&lt;/a&gt; Now, though, I’ve gone back to enjoying life offline. I don’t foresee myself craving social media, or online discourse, again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to support writers without buying books</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5350/" />
    <updated>2021-11-13T08:26:55Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5350/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One sure fire way to support the writers you love is to buy their books. If you buy their books, the authors receive royalties. With these royalties, authors make enough income to write something else. While it’s true that writers don’t make as much as they should make due to a number of factors, buying books by authors you love is a solid way to help them. If you’re low income, however, or don’t have enough money to buy books, there’s a number of other ways you can support authors without spending money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying books is the most direct way to support authors. Even so, there are many ways you can support writers without spending money on their books. Most of these alternatives will have the reader taking time out of their day to support the writer, but these alternatives will give your favorite writer a helping hand in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;promote-them-through-libraries&quot;&gt;Promote them through libraries.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libraries are great for everybody. They help low income readers get a chance to try your favorite author. They provide the author with free exposure by exposing their book to its many patrons. Libraries buy books recommended to them, so the author is still making money through libraries. Libraries buy books directly from publishers, so for each purchase, that author is making a royalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a book is very popular in a library, digital or physical, the library will buy more of that digital or physical book. Authors make money because the library buys directly from the publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you don’t use a local library, recommending that a library buy your favorite author’s book will ensure that your favorite author gets on shelves and into new readers hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unable to use a library, recommending a library buy your favorite authors book is the best way to support your favorite author. Usually, libraries have an online system that allows you to recommend a book if they don’t have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check and see if a library has a book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/&quot;&gt;use WorldCat&lt;/a&gt; because it’s a world wide database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, recommend your local schools buy the book for their school’s library. Call the school library directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the publisher name, title, author, and ISBN ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;help-translate-work&quot;&gt;Help translate work.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If language skills are your specialty, you can help authors translate their work into multiple languages. Some small publishers will even pay you to translate their authors books, but not all publishers are willing to allow translations. Smaller publishers are far easier to work with but the easiest books to translate are &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Category:Book&quot;&gt;books under a Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/&quot;&gt;public domain books.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If authors publish work under a creative commons license, respect the license the work is under. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2017/04/07/off-the-grid-living-blind-without-the-internet/&quot;&gt;my first book is under the least restrictive form of Creative Commons.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s some more resources for Creative Commons books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2009/08/13/google-books-adds-creative-commons-license-options/&quot;&gt;Google books has CC books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookshare.org/cms/search-freely-available&quot;&gt;Bookshare has fiction and nonfiction books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archiveofourown.org/&quot;&gt;Fanfiction&lt;/a&gt; is not under copyright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;plug-them-during-interviews&quot;&gt;Plug them during interviews.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re someone that gets interviewed a lot by podcasters, bloggers, or any other media figure, it costs nothing to plug your favorite author. Even if you’re not a writer yourself, chances are, you’re an expert in something, which is why the media is interviewing you. There’s always an opportunity to plug their name during the interview. The best link to plug when mentioning them is their website, not social media handles. Their website will last longer than a social media handle, most likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nominate-books-for-awards&quot;&gt;Nominate books for awards.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many awards judge suggestions by readers like you. Some awards come with cash prizes that can help the author write. Some come with other perks your favorite writer will find extremely useful and helpful. Even if they don’t win, they could be in the runner up section, which means your favorite author is getting recognition, which is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good place to find awards is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ala.org/alsc/awardsgrants/bookmedia&quot;&gt;this list of updating book awards&lt;/a&gt; so be sure to bookmark that link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the publication date, publication year, publisher, ISBN, title, author, and authors website handy as well as the book synopsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-a-letter-of-recommendation&quot;&gt;Write a letter of recommendation.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem a bit unusual at first, but I believe many fans can help writers out with grant applications in this way. In many residency applications, they require a letter from a third party as a testament to the writers dedication and or hard work. Many writers, like me, don’t have easy access to these kinds of letters, or can easily ask for these letters in enough time to complete the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write your letter on a formal letterhead or using a formal template. Avoid slang words and keep the letter professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-a-street-team&quot;&gt;Join a street team.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A street team is a dedicated group of volunteers that agree to promote an authors work in exchange for getting exclusive content. If you review books, joining a street team is a good way to ensure you get exclusive content including advanced reader copies, or advanced listener copies of a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be a member of the media to join a street team. If you’re willing to help in promotion of the book, or the author, you can join any authors street team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many authors run their street teams very differently from others. Some may give out bookmarks. Some may put you in acknowledgements of upcoming books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A street team is very different than a Patreon or donation. A street team is a willing exchange. Promotion of their work for exclusive content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many authors have different street team styles. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfks0lMp2tnrTTVeBg00Z5yEYTWeBSQzava3qjzxlrCuN7UOA/viewform?usp=sf_link&quot;&gt;my street team is an email list.&lt;/a&gt; Some authors will have a forum. Some authors will have an exclusive form so they can keep track of who’s promoting them and who isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a street team member, your duties may vary. Typically, you’ll be expected to promote their book on social media multiple times. You’ll be expected to ask your local library or bookstore to buy their books. If you review books, you’ll be expected to review their newest book every time they release a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the author publishes blogs, street team members could coordinate a social media campaign around the new post to boost the new blog post. A street team is a good faith promotional exchange and is vital to ensure a writer’s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every publisher has a publicist, so this is where street teams really help writers. If a writer is self-publishing their book, chances are, they won’t have a publicist. Not every publisher helps writers with promotion. In fact, it’s rare publishers assist writers with promotion, so this is another reason why a strong street team is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t join a street team unless you’re willing to promote the writer in multiple ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;suggest-indie-bookstores-buy-their-books&quot;&gt;Suggest indie bookstores buy their books.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many authors find immense success with independent bookstores. You can help out writers by recommending local indie bookstores buy copies of the authors books. Call, or email, the bookstore. Email is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to have the books publisher, distributor, ISBN, title, genre, and author ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/buy-local/9781990086083&quot;&gt;Indiebound is a great way to find bookstores near you.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;recommend-reviewers-review-books&quot;&gt;Recommend reviewers review books.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got a favorite podcaster or reviewer? Ask them to review your favorite book, even if you don’t listen to the show that often. Someone will like the review and then check out the author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to have a link to the publishers media page handy. If the publisher doesn’t have a media page, give them the publishers media contact email or phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;share-their-work&quot;&gt;Share their work.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more important than most would have you believe. Sharing an authors work to friends and family, as well as on your social media, helps immensely. It’s better if a lot of people are reading an author you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your favorite author doesn’t have a book coming out soon, share their blog, website, essay You’ve enjoyed, a short story you can’t stop thinking about. Tell others about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing is important. It boosts that authors presence. Share their work multiple times and in different venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! If you like my work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/donate/&quot;&gt;consider donating to me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Stock signings help me as a Disabled author.</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5299/" />
    <updated>2021-09-17T05:46:08Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5299/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aside from being an introvert, I am also Disabled. In particular, I’ve got two main disabilities. One is Cerebral Palsy. I’d consider this a secondary disability, but it does impact my speech. My primary disability is my blindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined, these two conditions can make author publicity extremely difficult for me. In particular, when it comes time to do author events and author book signings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned that I’m just simply not comfortable in extensive, in person, book signings and book events. For one thing, when a stammerer is talking endlessly for even a few minutes, that drains energy faster than a metaphor debate. It takes almost all of my spoons to speak to people, including verbally extensive question and answer sessions to boot. I try to save my verbal energy for things like Zoom meetings, testifying in court for my expert witness work, or podcast interviews, but when it comes time to promote my books, I’ve been expected to just try and do book signings and book events like everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/buy-local/9781990086083&quot;&gt;Artificial Divide,&lt;/a&gt; COVID-19 prevented large gatherings, essentially. I was happy about this because it gave me a chance to pitch some alternative marketing approaches that would be beneficial to keeping my energy and avoid burning out on book events while still giving readers an opportunity to take part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/calendar/&quot;&gt;I worked out multiple writing classes with the Chicago Public Library&lt;/a&gt; to give back to the community in various ways. I wanted to help other local marginalized authors while getting the word out about Artificial Divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A book signing technique with indie bookstores was a game changer for me in a good way. Typically, authors hold real time events at local bookstores, including live book signings. Because of the pandemic, I had to get creative. In the end, this new method of book signing, called, stock signing, is perfect for my disabilities and keeping spoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock signing is pretty straightforward. Authors first contact their local bookstore. In my case, I had multiple bookstores I wanted to try and build a relationship with, so I contacted all of my local bookstores within a two-mile radius of me. Authors pitch their book and ask if they have copies that they can stop by and sign on a day and time that’s convenient for the bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the bookstore has copies, great. If they don’t, pitch your book to them, especially if it’s distributed by Ingram. This was exceptionally easy to do via email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/buy-local/9781990086083&quot;&gt;Artificial Divide,&lt;/a&gt; many local bookstores already bought copies. This made scheduling to come in and sign them far easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After scheduling dates and times, go to the bookstore, sign a few, or more, copies, and then leave the store, making sure you know where the bookseller places special signed copies of books. Direct readers to that bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does two things. It puts the pressure off me because I’m not interacting with a whole crowd. It also gives me a chance to browse some audio books and get to know the bookstore manager better in person than a phone call or email. Phone calls take a lot out of me. Email is perfect for me, but technology can glitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had stores propose a consignment partnership with me. Even though I’ve done this before because that’s the only way many indie bookstores would buy the book, I’m just not very good at keeping up my own orders and inventory and stock. A lot of my smaller publishers didn’t do consignment deals directly so I had to have books shipped to me and then bring them to the store. This could be very problematic for other Disabled authors. In some cases, the publisher was willing to ship them directly to the indie bookstore of choice but that isn’t always possible. Because of my own travel limitations and other challenges, I typically don’t do consignment deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A consignment deal is where the author and bookstore work out an agreement where the author would sell directly to the bookstore and split profits. Usually, the split will be a 60/40 percent split with the bulk of the split going to the bookstore. Due to my various disabilities, however, a consignment deal isn’t always possible because of the bookstore policy or financial reasons. For example, what if a book doesn’t sell. I’d have to pick them up. I’d also need to pay a consignment fee in some cases, and I’d rather avoid fees, even if it’s a small fee like $25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d need to order books on behalf of the bookstore. I’d also be responsible for any lost or damaged books, and I’d rather take a very hands-off approach when selling books. I’d rather someone else handle everything. Sure, I could get more money doing a consignment deal, but that’s a lot of responsibility I simply don’t want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing stock in indie bookstores gives me a chance to direct customers to a bookstore and give them some publicity in addition to sales. It also allows me to develop one on one relationships with the various employees in the store. They, in turn, are enthusiastic about supporting me and will aid me in promotion. I’ve even been asked to be a guest speaker at some local events inside bookstores where I’ve done stock signings because I’ve developed a long-lasting relationship with the bookstore manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock signing could be an effective marketing strategy for Disabled authors that, like me, simply just don’t do well in crowds or large gatherings. There are many benefits involved for everybody, including your readers. They have a location they can reserve signed copies and they can arrange pickup times with the bookstore rather than with you directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find events exhausting or unworkable, stock signing is an excellent compromise for a lot of benefits to gain in return.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tools for Disabled writers</title>
    <link href="/myblog/posts/5273/" />
    <updated>2021-08-24T03:50:48Z</updated>
    <id>/myblog/posts/5273/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I had it my way, publishing would be a lot more accommodating to Disabled authors regardless of fabulousness, but, unfortunately, publishing still has a mountain to climb when it comes to treating Disabled authors as well as it treats status quo authors, especially Disabled authors of color including Black Disabled authors and indigenous Disabled authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there’s still a mountain to climb regarding accessibility and inclusion, I’d figure I’d try to do my part to make it easier on Disabled writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the best way for me to help others open doors is to give them tools to struggle less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;converting-markdown-to-shun-format&quot;&gt;Converting Markdown to Shun format.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2023/03/10/how-to-convert-markdown-to-shun-manuscript-format/&quot;&gt;I wrote this tutorial explaining how to convert Markdown manuscripts into Shun manuscript format for Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;paying-markets-rss-feed&quot;&gt;Paying markets RSS feed.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/paying-markets/&quot;&gt;a freely available RSS feed of paying markets.&lt;/a&gt; I want other Disabled authors to succeed. Of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/paying-markets/&quot;&gt;the RSS feed that updates with paying markets&lt;/a&gt; won’t solve all systemic problems, but it does cut down on having to search for paying markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The linked items go directly to the original posts, always giving the original poster traffic to the pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m always open to finding more resources I can turn into tools for others so don’t be afraid to get in touch with resources. The paying markets tool isn’t the only tool I’ve created, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-manuscript-format-templates-for-word&quot;&gt;Modern manuscript format templates for Word.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I strongly think &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/2021/07/11/submission-accessibility-for-literary-agents-and-editors/&quot;&gt;editors should provide their own templates when creating submission guidelines,&lt;/a&gt; I’ve created a Microsoft Word template that should take the Burdon out of formatting a short story or novel. I’ve also included an anonymous template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My template is based off &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shunn.net/format/templates.html&quot;&gt;Shunn’s Word templates&lt;/a&gt; but with a few things changed. Some of his macros conflicted with Word’s modern keyboard shortcuts so I changed some macros around and added some macros to make basic cleanup far easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a templates package based off the proper manuscript format. The templates come packaged in a zip file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rkingett/writertools/files/6766580/New.accessible.manuscript.format.templates.zip&quot;&gt;Download version 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rkingett/writertools/releases&quot;&gt;view the releases page for later versions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These templates are fully accessible to screen readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure the macros work, you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/enable-or-disable-macros-in-office-files-12b036fd-d140-4e74-b45e-16fed1a7e5c6&quot;&gt;enable macros in Microsoft Word.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rkingett/writertools/wiki&quot;&gt;The wiki page&lt;/a&gt; serves as a guide to the templates and how to use the macros. Of course, all of this is free and open source. If you can improve on my work, do it. Make it better and easier to use. I’ll explain some differences between the old templates and my modern templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titles, such as story title, chapter titles, and novel title, are all headings. Main titles are heading level one. Subtitles and chapter names are heading level two. This should make it far easier for people to skim their documents as well as allow screen reader users to jump sections in their manuscripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a macro that will do basic cleanup. Remove extra white space at the end of paragraphs. Remove extra line and paragraph spacing. Removes double punctuation marks at the ends of sentences. Removes all extra spaces between words, such as when someone accidentally hits the spacebar twice, and more. this macro is called QuickFix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created macros to automatically insert chapters when needed. Press Alt, C, Charlie, to create a new chapter with a number. Press Alt T, tango, to create a new chapter with chapter title. You will have to go back and replace the, X, after the word, chapter, but it works. It will automatically place your cursor into the proper place for typing your body text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word has a longstanding bug where if you put a quote before a letter after the previous sentence, this letter isn’t capitalized. It’s caused many problems for me when writing dialog after finishing a sentence. This second macro fixes that bug. When you run the, CleanDialog, macro, it capitalizes every letter after an opening quotation mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My templates will automatically count words for you and round them to the nearest hundred or nearest thousand. These fields are already in their correct places in the document. These fields don’t require macros to run but there is a macro that will automatically update the fields upon closing your document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I’d like to share a tip in case you’d rather just create some macros or templates yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-your-own-word-count-macro&quot;&gt;Create your own word count macro.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this trick is mainly for VI writers, others can use this trick too. Here’s how to automatically round words in a Microsoft Word document using a screen reader and the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a bit of an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;proper-manuscript-format-explanation&quot;&gt;Proper manuscript format explanation.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When submitting to pro markets, the submission guidelines require that the manuscript be formatted in, what’s known, as proper manuscript format. AKA, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shunn.net/format/story.html&quot;&gt;Shunn manuscript format&lt;/a&gt;. This format has a lot of visual specifications that make it easier to read manuscripts. It, also, though, puts a ton of extra work on those of us that are blind or visually impaired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the same, fiction and nonfiction publications like this format. Book publishers love this format. Even if they don’t say they want this style, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.office.com/en-us/article/change-the-normal-template-normal-dotm-06de294b-d216-47f6-ab77-ccb5166f98ea&quot;&gt;change your normal template&lt;/a&gt; to this style anyway, just because it will make your life easier in the long run. Plus, it looks professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d suggest you use the below templates and make changes to them. These templates are the only screen reader friendly ones I could find, so far. I’ve included an anonymous template because some pro publications do blind readings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shunn.net/format/templates.html&quot;&gt;Shunn templates.&lt;/a&gt; Made for Word 2007 but is screen reader friendly. There is no modern version that’s screen reader friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1u_K-tLjvCzwrXZORb4xiR83pWHzKPuEyE3T-thGKah8/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Anonymous template.&lt;/a&gt; Provided by the very inclusive folks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://escapeartists.net/&quot;&gt;Escape Artists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your template, let’s get counting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d suggest you practice on the below with a document first, not a template. When you’re ready to edit a template, open the template with Control O, as you would a regular document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;counting-words-using-fields&quot;&gt;Counting words using fields.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s tiring to have to open up the word count dialog, copy that number, then paste it in the document. It’s far better if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.office.com/en-us/article/use-fields-to-insert-word-count-in-your-document-8696d5ae-25bb-4173-a76f-00f213a2fa63&quot;&gt;insert a field that will count words for you&lt;/a&gt; into the Normal template so you won’t have to enter the number every time you want to write a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of your template, delete the numeral that says 100 words. This numeral is aligned a certain way, so be careful not to delete the tab stop before the word, about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, 100, is deleted, do the following to insert an automatic word count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place the cursor exactly where the 100 was or wherever you want this field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press CTRL F9. NVDA won’t speak at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type, NumWords without spaces or pressing anything else. The label has two capital letters in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press F9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update the count, select the field and press F9. Alternatively, select the whole document, CTRL A, and hit F9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also update the field automatically. Here’s how to automatically update all fields when closing a document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Record your Macro. Name it, AutoClose. Make sure the, A, and C, are capitalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To open the Record Macro dialog, press Alt+W, M, R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type AutoClose as a name for your macro, and then press Enter. The name cannot contain spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record the macro by performing the commands or pressing the keys for the steps in the task. Word records your keystrokes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the macro is recording, press, CTRL A. Then, F9. Then, CTRL S. Don’t do anything else!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To stop recording, press Alt+W, M, R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re done! If you put this macro in your modified normal template, your workflow will be basically automated. Now, onto rounding the above field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;automatically-round-word-count-fields&quot;&gt;Automatically round word count fields.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason you may want to insert a rounded number rather than an exact number is because it makes writing cover letters easier. It also makes looking for paying markets easier. Always look for markets that are 100 words higher than your rounded count, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Control-F9. You are now in a field. NVDA does not speak, at all, so you need to be very good with keyboards and cursors here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the field, type, =ROUND(,-2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the rounding function, where the -2 indicates how many digits you want rounded off. If it were -3, it would be to the nearest thousand. Case isn’t important: you can type =ROUND or =round or anything in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your cursor between the left parron, ( and the comma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Control-F9 again to get another field inside the first one. NVDA will not speak, at all, but you are exactly where you need to be. Don’t press any other keys!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type the field name, NUMWORDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;press F9 to update the field. Alternatively, Toggle the whole thing so it shows as text, either by hitting Shift F10 and choosing “Update field” from the context menu or by pressing Alt-F9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, your field code looks something like this, using {} for the special field characters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=round({ numwords }, -2 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a few tries to get it right so always make a backup copy. Try doing the above on a document first, rather than a template to be sure you got the hang of it. When you’re ready, apply it to your actual template so you never have to do this again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, backup your writing templates in OneDrive so it travels with you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.office.com/en-us/article/basic-tasks-using-a-screen-reader-with-onedrive-49bc76ad-4c47-4772-af75-657ac99921be#picktab=windows&quot;&gt;OneDrive is accessible to screen readers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you liked this post, and enjoy my fiction work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertkingett.com/donate/&quot;&gt;donate to me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy writing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
